<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antitrust &amp;amp; Competition Policy on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/antitrust-amp-competition-policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antitrust &amp;amp; Competition Policy on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/antitrust-amp-competition-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There are good reasons to be skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the threat of automation, I agree with Ryan Khurana: “From self-driving car crashes to failed workplace algorithms, many AI tools fail to perform simple tasks humans excel at, let alone far surpass us in every way.” Like myself, he is skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market, pointing out that “[The] conflation of what AI ‘may one day do’ with the much more mundane ‘what software can do today’ creates a powerful narrative around automation that accepts no refutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Kill Zone in Tech?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 22:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Noah Smith explored an emerging question in tech. Is there a kill zone where new and innovative upstarts are being throttled by the biggest players? He explains,
So, are American tech companies making it difficult for startups? Perhaps, but there are some other reasons to be skeptical.
First off, the nature of the venture capital market has changed due to the declining costs of computing. Not too long ago, much of a tech company’s Series A and B would be dedicated to buying server racks and computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did The Supreme Court Get The Market Definition Correct In The Amex Case?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 20:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Supreme Court is winding down for the year and last week put out a much awaited decision in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-1454_5h26.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ohio v. American Express&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Some have rung the alarm with this case, but I think caution is worthwhile. In short, the Court’s analysis wasn’t expansive like some have claimed, but incomplete. There are a lot of important details to this case and the guideposts it has provided will likely be fought over in future litigation over platform regulation. To narrow the scope of this post, I am going to focus on the market definition question and the issue of two-sided platforms in light of the developments in the industrial organization (IO) literature in the past two decades.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learn From Past Government-Imposed Corporate Breakups Is That They Don&#39;t Work</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/what-we-learn-from-past-government-imposed-corporate-breakups-is-that-they-dont-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 18:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/what-we-learn-from-past-government-imposed-corporate-breakups-is-that-they-dont-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Voices from all over the political and professional spectrum have been clamoring for tech companies to be broken up. T&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ech investor &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/15/roger-mcnamee-google-should-be-broken-up-into-8-companies.html&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Roger McNamee,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;machine learning pioneer Yoshua Bengio&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axios.com/the-case-for-breaking-up-big-tech-1516625369-8695e00f-4e82-4ba1-ae89-abcd17e2a1ee.html&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;NYU professor Scott Galloway&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Marco Rubio’s 2016 presidential digital director&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; have all suggested that tech companies should be forcibly separated. So,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; I took a look at some of the past efforts in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanactionforum.org/insight/a-history-of-failure-government-imposed-corporate-breakups/&#34;&gt;new survey of corporate breakups&lt;/a&gt; and found that they really weren’t all that effective at creating competitive markets.&lt;br&gt;
Although many consider &lt;em&gt;Standard Oil&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/em&gt; as classic cases, I think &lt;em&gt;United States v. American Tobacco Company&lt;/em&gt; is far more instructive. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandating AI Fairness May Come At The Expense Of Other Types of Fairness</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/mandating-ai-fairness-may-come-at-the-expense-of-other-types-of-fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 18:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/mandating-ai-fairness-may-come-at-the-expense-of-other-types-of-fairness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, ProPublica &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing&#34;&gt;initiated a conversation&lt;/a&gt; over the use of risk assessment algorithms when they concluded that a widely used “score proved remarkably unreliable in forecasting violent crime” in Florida. Their examination of the racial disparities in scoring has been cited countless times, often as a proxy for the power of automation and algorithms in daily life. Indeed, as the authors concluded, these scores are “part of a part of a larger examination of the powerful, largely hidden effect of algorithms in American life.”&lt;br&gt;
As this examination continues, two precepts are worth keeping in mind. First, the social significance of algorithms needs to be considered, not just their internal model significance. While the accuracy of algorithms are important, more emphasis should be placed on how they are used within institutional settings. And second, fairness is not a single idea. Mandates for certain kinds of fairness could come at the expense of others forms of fairness. As always, policymakers need to be cognizant of the trade offs.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
