<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hill Profiles Gigi Sohn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</guid>
      <description>Julian Hattem has a profile of Gigi Sohn, charting her influence over the network neutrality debate. The former head of an advocacy organization now leads from the inside:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics of Euvoluntary Exchange</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samuel Wilson’s prodigious and interesting output at &lt;a href=&#34;http://euvoluntaryexchange.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary Exchange&lt;/a&gt; lead me to two articles by Michael Munger, the source of the blog’s name and focus. The first article “&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.duke.edu/~munger/euvol.pdf&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary or Not, Exchange is Just&lt;/a&gt;” is fascinating. Here is the main thesis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Munger, euvoluntary exchange is the name given to any any truly voluntary exchange that leaves both parties better off than before. To be truly voluntary or euvoluntary, the exchange requires&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information wants to be expensive as well as free</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</guid>
      <description>Famously, Stewart Brand noted that “information wants to be free.” But, that statement leaves off the other half of the phrase, thus burying the complexity of his thinking. In an email, he explained,
He continues in his book, “The MIT Media Lab”:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAA Device Rules and the Continuing Problem of Spectrum Interference</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</guid>
      <description>This was bound to happen: the proliferation of mobile devices is beginning to cause the “incidents” involving airline passengers to rack up. From Nick Bilton:
At issue is the largely unproven idea that tablets and phones interfere with a plane’s computers and communication devices. But, the asymmetry in rules for flight and takeoff is especially peculiar. When electromagnetic interference does happen with mobile devices, it is usually limited to a narrowband of the spectrum, due to inadequate filtering, tuning, or poor frequency control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon &amp; Their Taxes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 21:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Reuters is reporting on the history and legal problems of Amazon’s taxes. Apparently, last year the IRS demanded $1.5 billion in back-taxes from “transfer pricing [of their] our foreign subsidiaries,” amounting to just under a tenth of their gross annual profit.
The article doesn’t take much knowledge of tax law to understand, but for the tl:dr crowd, here is the gist:
In 1999, Amazon began to bring foreign profits home from their French and British operations to balance the losses in the US, which at the time amounted to over $1 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulf Between Libertarians and Other Social Theorists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know why I have never considered it before, but Ross Kenyon is correct:
Methodologically, libertarians and Austrians see the world largely as aggregated individuals, compared to other social theorists who mainly consider the world through group level dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbert Spencer on the Right to Ignore the State</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 16:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</guid>
      <description>From Social Statics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inseparability of Rights and Duties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>On rights and duties by James Otteson:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multistakeholder Meeting Illuminates Various Problems of Objectivity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>At the NTIA Multistakeholder Meeting this week, it was suggested that all those studies submitted and funded by an outside source be disclosed. Later, when the issue of objectivity came up again, it was suggested that the group should rely on professors to provide objective views. While I am for disclosure in practice and not necessarily against the academy, both of the suggestions belie a flawed, but pervasive, vision on the connection between objectivity and research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conflict of Visions Does Not Align Well With Parties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</guid>
      <description>Charles Murray’s review of Thomas Sowell’s “A Conflict of Visions: Ideological Origins of Political Struggles” begins:
While I tend to think Sowell’s thesis explains a lot for the libertarian/non-libertarian divide, it is not so clear that the left/right divide aligns as well. Both parties use the government to enact their preferred area of concern. It just happens that the traditional Right tends to concern itself with social issues while the Left does so with economic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Great Sentences for Libertarians</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</guid>
      <description>From “Why Teaching Equality Hurts Men,”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Richard Pipes’ “Property and Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>No society has ever existed without some kind of property, the vision of an ideal propertyless world must be grounded not in collective memory but in a collective longing. p 5
  Politics for those in The Republic were largely a matter of custom, not law. Hence for Plato, the ideal state would have no statutes. According to Plutarch, Lycurgus would not permit the rules he laid down for Sparta to be committed to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The police state began with the Inquisition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</guid>
      <description>This article, and the book that it is based on, seem hugely provocative:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Postmodernism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</guid>
      <description>The opening to “The End of Sociological Theory” by Steven Seidman:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilitarianism Doesn’t Ask the Kinds of Questions I Care About</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 18:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I noted,
Since Socrates, we have been enamored with the question of the good life. What is the good life? How do we create the good life? What will the world look like when we implement the good life? Religion is an answer to this question, but at their core, each are questions about which.
Which values are good?
But these values are in constant flux. We have dialogues about them, and even so, it is hard to say that when we make decisions, we are basing these decisions on some sort of ethical/moral guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McCloskey Explains the Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/mccloskey-explains-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 14:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/mccloskey-explains-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>McCloskey critiquing Marxism, extreme leftism and general allocation economics:
 No version of accumulation can explain the modern world, or else the modern world would have been ancient, since accumulation was.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Profane</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 16:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fundamental distinctions in human thought is between the profane (profanum) and sacred (sacrum). Summarized by Nisbet,
The opposite of this is the profane, which is the utilitarian, individualistic world that we all inhabit. To see it another way, the profane revolves around the concerns of the individuals, while the sacred includes the concerns of the community. As Durkheim explained, people feel that the moral truths of the sacred are far more important than just personal preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Course Free Press Authored It</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</guid>
      <description>From the, “Yes, of course we all knew this” file,
I think its great that an organization helping to solve the Internet’s problems cannot even delete the metadata. Really?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tony Judt is wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>I just read a new essay from Tony Judt he wrote in the New York Times Book Review. For me, the takeaway part was the very beginning where he said,
Later, he laments, saying,
With the worst of the economic crisis behind us, social commentators like Judt are calling for action, demanding that leaders and society change to advert another economic crisis. Sadly, this is yet another lofty aspiration based on fallacious Enlightenment ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
