<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Tech on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/mobile-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile Tech on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 19:32:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/mobile-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Value As a Result of Pricing Mobile Data Use</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 19:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</guid>
      <description>I was reading over the comments my former colleagues at the International Center for Law and Economics and TechFreedom filed on Title II reclassification to find these two paragraphs of pure Alchian bliss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Undermines Prevailing Theory that Technology is Isolating</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</guid>
      <description>An ever-present theme in the commentary of modern technology is its isolating effect. Yet the truth is far more complex. This Boston Review article on technology points to a paper supported by the Annenberg School of Communication that seems to suggest we are becoming more social. By conducting a content analysis of films from four public spaces over a thirty-year period, the behavior and characteristics of 143,593 people were coded. A couple of key findings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report Reiterates Axiom: Restrictive Spectrum Rules Unsuccessful</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/report-reiterates-axiom-restrictive-spectrum-rules-unsuccessful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 19:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/report-reiterates-axiom-restrictive-spectrum-rules-unsuccessful/</guid>
      <description>A report released today reiterates much of what we already know: restrictive spectrum rules aimed at achieving specific policy goals are mostly unsuccessful. I have previously written on this topic for the UK, which the report outlines in more detail, but both Canada and Germany have faced serious challenges and market distortions because of restrictive spectrum rules:
 In Germany, where regulators restricted participation in the 3G auction through spectrum caps, two new entrants withdrew from the market without deploying the newly acquired spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAA Device Rules and the Continuing Problem of Spectrum Interference</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</guid>
      <description>This was bound to happen: the proliferation of mobile devices is beginning to cause the “incidents” involving airline passengers to rack up. From Nick Bilton:
At issue is the largely unproven idea that tablets and phones interfere with a plane’s computers and communication devices. But, the asymmetry in rules for flight and takeoff is especially peculiar. When electromagnetic interference does happen with mobile devices, it is usually limited to a narrowband of the spectrum, due to inadequate filtering, tuning, or poor frequency control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Industries and the Telecom Sector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>The classical definition of competitive price are those where price equal cost. The thought being, if a producer pushes their price above this line, they will not be able to capture customers, and if they lower their prices, they will not be able to cover their cost. We often think of cost as the money one spend to produce an item, but it includes more; there is there also the cost of managing the firm, and importantly it includes the minimum level of profit the firm must return to be attractive to investors and thus have capital inflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and iAd</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</guid>
      <description>I really don’t know how this went past me, but I was watching Fast Money today and Kaminsky made note of Apple going into direct search. To make this a little more solid, look at this,
The always insightful Picard makes this more tangible:
Only time will allow us to understand how this is going to work out, but regardless, it is an interesting time to be in media.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
