<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 20:02:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Famous Psychological Experiment Has Serious Flaws</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 20:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</guid>
      <description>As you might recall, the Stanford Prison Experiment pitted several student against each other as randomly chosen prison guards or prisoners. The end result was quite gruesome. Guards enforced authoritarian measures and even inflicted psychological torture on the prisoners. The experiment is a classic note in psychology texts and has often been used to explain the Nazis, Abu Ghraib, and other forms of inhumane practices.
Apparently, there are serious flaws with the study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The police state began with the Inquisition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</guid>
      <description>This article, and the book that it is based on, seem hugely provocative:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Profane</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 16:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fundamental distinctions in human thought is between the profane (profanum) and sacred (sacrum). Summarized by Nisbet,
The opposite of this is the profane, which is the utilitarian, individualistic world that we all inhabit. To see it another way, the profane revolves around the concerns of the individuals, while the sacred includes the concerns of the community. As Durkheim explained, people feel that the moral truths of the sacred are far more important than just personal preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
