<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Telecom &amp;amp; Cable Regulation on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/telecom-amp-cable-regulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Telecom &amp;amp; Cable Regulation on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:49:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/telecom-amp-cable-regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Legal Advisories on the New Net Neutrality Rules</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>The new network neutrality rules have been out for almost a month now. Here is a short collection of legal opinions:
 “Net Neutrality V.3: What We Know So Far” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “A First Look Inside the Net Neutrality Order” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “The FCC’s Open Internet Order: New Net Neutrality Rules and Title II Regulation of Broadband” by Bennett L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Competition in Network Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Alissa Cooper, formerly at CDT and now at Cisco, wrote her PhD dissertation on network neutrality practices in the US and the UK. Here is an interesting tidbit from her abstract:
In many European countries, unbundling has lead to competition among providers. While this has put downward pressure on consumer prices, investment in the backbone is far lower. Altogether, these industry features often lead companies pricing data since their margins are low, thus leading to very schemes that network neutrality advocates deplore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s The FCC’s Rush on New Net Neutrality Rules?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>Network neutrality rules have failed to pass Congress and the courts countless times, so what’s the FCC’s rush now? Scott Cleland explores in an op-ed at the Daily Caller:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Economic Environment Will TV Unbundling Create?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 22:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</guid>
      <description>The Technology Policy Institute just went live with a video of their OTT event, exploring TV unbundling. There is a lot of solid material, but Laura Martin, a Senior Analyst at Needham &amp;amp; Company, explained what would happen if we went to an unbundled world:
 As soon as you unbundle, you lose advertising revenue. Immediately, you have to double the cost because of lost ad dollars. 1/2 of the revenues come from ads and the other 1/2 comes from subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is STELA the Vehicle for Video Reform?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/is-stela-the-vehicle-for-video-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 18:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/is-stela-the-vehicle-for-video-reform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though few things are getting passed this Congress, the pressure is on to reauthorize the Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act (STELA) before it expires at the end of this year. Unsurprisingly, many have hoped this “must pass bill” will be the vehicle for broader reform of video. Getting video law right is important for our content rich world, but the discussion needs to expand much further than STELA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Course Free Press Authored It</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</guid>
      <description>From the, “Yes, of course we all knew this” file,
I think its great that an organization helping to solve the Internet’s problems cannot even delete the metadata. Really?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasmussen, the FCC and Rape Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Adam Thierer over at Technology Liberation Front posted a Rasmussen poll that suggests,
He believes that it is due to FCC’s overreaching actions:
It is actually a little simpler than that. I don’t think many people know or even care about the FCC and Internet regulation. The story that broke this past week, which is probably the cause of this drop, more broadly fits into the concept of intrusion, which has been all the rage these past couple months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
