<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Paradoxes Of Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>Svetlana Boym has a fascinating article on nostalgia. Here are some choice parts:
Interesting essay throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Technological / Cultural Determinism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 03:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</guid>
      <description>Alex Parrish begins “Adaptive Rhetoric: Evolution, Culture, and the Art of Persuasion” by recalling a story about one reaction to his book, and in doing so, helps to explain the problem of the technological/cultural determinism debate:
Parrish is right. The either/or presentation of culture and biology leads us to believe that one must take precedent in guiding behavior. The same kind of criticism can be heaped on the technological/cultural determinist deabate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Technology, the Past is No Longer a Foreign Country</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</guid>
      <description>Novelist L. P. Hartley once wrote, “The past is a foreign country: they do things differently there.” Ironically, we may no longer live in his world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulf Between Libertarians and Other Social Theorists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know why I have never considered it before, but Ross Kenyon is correct:
Methodologically, libertarians and Austrians see the world largely as aggregated individuals, compared to other social theorists who mainly consider the world through group level dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbert Spencer on the Right to Ignore the State</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 16:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</guid>
      <description>From Social Statics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inseparability of Rights and Duties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>On rights and duties by James Otteson:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conflict of Visions Does Not Align Well With Parties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</guid>
      <description>Charles Murray’s review of Thomas Sowell’s “A Conflict of Visions: Ideological Origins of Political Struggles” begins:
While I tend to think Sowell’s thesis explains a lot for the libertarian/non-libertarian divide, it is not so clear that the left/right divide aligns as well. Both parties use the government to enact their preferred area of concern. It just happens that the traditional Right tends to concern itself with social issues while the Left does so with economic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Postmodernism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</guid>
      <description>The opening to “The End of Sociological Theory” by Steven Seidman:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilitarianism Doesn’t Ask the Kinds of Questions I Care About</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 18:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I noted,
Since Socrates, we have been enamored with the question of the good life. What is the good life? How do we create the good life? What will the world look like when we implement the good life? Religion is an answer to this question, but at their core, each are questions about which.
Which values are good?
But these values are in constant flux. We have dialogues about them, and even so, it is hard to say that when we make decisions, we are basing these decisions on some sort of ethical/moral guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Quotes on ‘The Foucault Effect: Studies in Governmentality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 22:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks, I have been become fascinated with the the history of policing, an area of dire import for libertarians of all stripes. Originally, the word police was synonymous with policy as we know it today e.g. civil administration, but slowly it began to take a different tact around the time when the modern state and economy were coming into their own. According to the etymology dictionary, the first force so-named in England was the Marine Police, set up 1798 to protect merchandise at the Port of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 05:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</guid>
      <description>Rationality is only an instrument. It is a tool to achieving goals. Where do these goals come from? That is the better question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phrases Worth Remembering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 04:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</guid>
      <description> Ideology is rhetorical. Privacy is not an value. It is a means to protecting other values. Academic thought is revolutionary, policy is marginalist. Germany was unified in 1871.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information, Episteme and Techne Part 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading about information and stumbled upon an OED entry on the subject. As Michael Proffitt, managing editor, OED said, “Compounds arising in that period [the 1800s] reflect information as a commodity with supply and demand: information-giving (dating from 1829), information-seeking (1869), information gathering (1893).”
Proffitt is mistaken about about the commodity metaphor, and it is a similar one made in Marxist and Marxian thought. Once you make a concept a commodity, you have stripped it of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy and Freewill in a Previous Era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 02:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</guid>
      <description>For the pre-Socratic authors, tragedy was a very simple thing. Homer, being the bridge between the archaic and the ancient, exemplified this tragedy. Tragedy for this group was mankind going against fate. Tragedy was man’s betting of his own ability (hubris) against what the gods knew to be the future. This is why tragedy has been such a powerful story over the ages, I would argue. It taps into this very old, perhaps even subconscious belief that things in the world are ordered and thus determined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
