<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscellaneous on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscellaneous on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 13:20:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reviving the Office of Technology Assessment would require a set of specific conditions in Congress. We have simply not arrived at that time.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/reviving-the-office-of-technology-assessment-would-require-a-set-of-specific-conditions-in-congress-we-have-simply-not-arrived-at-that-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/reviving-the-office-of-technology-assessment-would-require-a-set-of-specific-conditions-in-congress-we-have-simply-not-arrived-at-that-time/</guid>
      <description>Cato Unbound is taking on the issue of tech expertise this month and the lead essay came from Kevin Kosar, who argues for the revival of the Office of Technology Assessment. As he explains,
He continues, “Congress’s ineptitude in [science and technology policy] has been richly displayed.” To help embed expertise in science and technology policy, Kosar argues for the revival of the Office of Technology Assessment, which was established in 1972 and defunded in 1995.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Broadband Isn’t Like Rural Electrification, It Is So Much Harder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/rural-broadband-isnt-like-rural-electrification-it-is-so-much-harder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/rural-broadband-isnt-like-rural-electrification-it-is-so-much-harder/</guid>
      <description>Many have likened efforts to build out rural broadband today to the accomplishments of rural electrification in the 1930s. But the two couldn’t be further from each other. From the structure of the program and underlying costs, to the impact on productivity, rural electrification is drastically different than current efforts to get broadband in rural regions. My recent piece at ReaclClearPolicy explores some of those differences, but there is one area I wasn’t able to explore, the question of cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kids Are Going To Be Alright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</guid>
      <description>Catchy headlines like “Heavy Social Media Use Linked With Mental Health Issues In Teens” and “Have Smartphones Destroyed a Generation?” advance a common trope of generational decline. But a new paper in Nature uses a new and rigorous analytical method to understand the relationship between adolescent well-being and digital technology, finding a “negative but small [link], explaining at most 0.4% of the variation in well-being.”
What really sets apart the new paper from Amy Orben and Andy Przybylski is that it aims to capture a more complete picture of how variables interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you’re worried about net neutrality, put your reputation on the line and make a prediction about the future</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/if-youre-worried-about-net-neutrality-put-your-reputation-on-the-line-and-make-a-prediction-about-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 14:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/if-youre-worried-about-net-neutrality-put-your-reputation-on-the-line-and-make-a-prediction-about-the-future/</guid>
      <description>It is now been a year since network neutrality rules supported by Title II were officially repealed, marking the end of the Obama-era legislation. Writing in Wired, Klint Finley noted that, “The good news is that the internet isn’t drastically different than it was before. But that’s also the bad news: The net wasn’t always so neutral to begin with.”
At the time, many worried what would happen. Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak and former FCC Commissioner Michael Copps suggested that two worlds were possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Short Responses To The Pacing Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</guid>
      <description>Contemporary tech criticism displays an anti-nostalgia. Instead of being reverent for the past, anxiety about the future abounds. In these visions, the future is imagined as a strange, foreign land, beset with problems. And yet, to quote that old adage, tomorrow is the visitor that is always coming but never arrives. The future never arrives because we are assembling it today.
The distance between the now and the future finds its hook in tech policy in the pacing problem, a term describing the mismatch between advancing technologies and society’s efforts to cope with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should The New NPR Poll On Rural America Make You Reconsider Your View of Rural Broadband Development?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/should-the-new-npr-poll-on-rural-america-make-you-reconsider-your-view-of-rural-broadband-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/should-the-new-npr-poll-on-rural-america-make-you-reconsider-your-view-of-rural-broadband-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;National Public Radio, the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, and the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health just published a new report on “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/HARVARD-POLL/rural-health-poll-10-15-18-updated.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Life in Rural America&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.” This survey of 1,300 adults living in the rural United States has a lot to say about health issues, population change, the strengths and challenges for rural communities, as well as discrimination and drug use. But I wanted to highlight two questions related to rural broadband development that might make you update your beliefs about massive rural investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
