<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:59:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zuboff’s “The Age of Surveillance Capitalism” raw notes and comments on the definition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/zuboffs-the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-raw-notes-and-comments-on-the-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/zuboffs-the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-raw-notes-and-comments-on-the-definition/</guid>
      <description>Shoshana Zuboff’s book “The Age of Surveillance Capitalism” set a new tone in tech analysis since it was published in January of 2019. In just a year, her term, surveillance capitalism, has become a dominant mode of analysis. This year I am going to read the book and then post raw notes and comments on the book. What follows are my thoughts on the first part dealing with the definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Value Data? A Reply To Jaron Lanier’s Op-Ed In The NYT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/how-do-you-value-data-a-reply-to-jaron-laniers-op-ed-in-the-nyt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 21:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/how-do-you-value-data-a-reply-to-jaron-laniers-op-ed-in-the-nyt/</guid>
      <description>Jaron Lanier was featured in a recent New York Times op-ed explaining why people should get paid for their data. Under this scheme, he estimates the total value of data for a four person household could fetch around $20,000.
Let’s do the math on that.
Data from eMarketer finds that users spend about an hour and fifteen minutes per day on social media for a total of 456.25 hours per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are good reasons to be skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the threat of automation, I agree with Ryan Khurana: “From self-driving car crashes to failed workplace algorithms, many AI tools fail to perform simple tasks humans excel at, let alone far surpass us in every way.” Like myself, he is skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market, pointing out that “[The] conflation of what AI ‘may one day do’ with the much more mundane ‘what software can do today’ creates a powerful narrative around automation that accepts no refutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Short Responses To The Pacing Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</guid>
      <description>Contemporary tech criticism displays an anti-nostalgia. Instead of being reverent for the past, anxiety about the future abounds. In these visions, the future is imagined as a strange, foreign land, beset with problems. And yet, to quote that old adage, tomorrow is the visitor that is always coming but never arrives. The future never arrives because we are assembling it today.
The distance between the now and the future finds its hook in tech policy in the pacing problem, a term describing the mismatch between advancing technologies and society’s efforts to cope with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did The Facebook Stock Drop Last Week? Some Economics Of Decision-making</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 22:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A curious thing happened last week. Facebook’s stock, which had seem to have weathered the 2018 controversies, took a beating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the Washington Post, Craig Timberg and Elizabeth Dwoskin &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/07/26/how-years-privacy-controversies-finally-caught-up-with-facebook/?utm_term=.33e4676e4d41&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;explained&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;that the stock market drop was representative of a larger wave:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jeff Chester of the Center for Digital Democracy piled on, describing the drop as “a privacy wake-up call that the markets are delivering to Mark Zuckerberg.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;But the downward pressure was driven by more fundamental changes. Simply put, Facebook missed its earnings target. But it is important to peer into why the company didn’t meet those targets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into the Regulation Market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</guid>
      <description>In response to the new Tyler Cowen and Alex Alex Tabarrok piece on information asymmetry, Arnold Kling wonders if:
My response:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meritocracy in Blogging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/meritocracy-in-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 14:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/meritocracy-in-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Stories like this really push back against the filter bubble thesis:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Tastes in the Top 40 &amp; Some Economics of Music</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 15:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</guid>
      <description>A back and forth has popped up about the Top 40. It began with Libby Jacobson comparing a Top 40 list from 1996 and today. As she points out, even though only Alanis Morissette was the only one to have two songs in the Top 40, today the Top 40 shows much less variety:
Ultimately, Jacobson concludes that “pop music is converging both in terms of style/sound and in terms of the talent &amp;amp; personalities producing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micropayments, The News, &amp; Friction Free Browsing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 19:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week I heard Walter Isaacson delve into his new book, “The Innovators,” at the American Enterprise Institute. In discussion, he lamented the development of the various business models in online journalism, and content generally, arguing forcefully for micropayments in their place. In a LinkedIn article on the same subject, he explains:
Even though I am not in the prediction business, I am highly skeptical that micropayments will become widespread for a number of reasons, none of which are particularly new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics of Euvoluntary Exchange</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samuel Wilson’s prodigious and interesting output at &lt;a href=&#34;http://euvoluntaryexchange.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary Exchange&lt;/a&gt; lead me to two articles by Michael Munger, the source of the blog’s name and focus. The first article “&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.duke.edu/~munger/euvol.pdf&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary or Not, Exchange is Just&lt;/a&gt;” is fascinating. Here is the main thesis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Munger, euvoluntary exchange is the name given to any any truly voluntary exchange that leaves both parties better off than before. To be truly voluntary or euvoluntary, the exchange requires&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Genesis of the Career Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 16:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>I have begun in earnest to read through Annalee Saxenian’s “Regional Advantage,” charting the computer industry’s genesis in both Silicon Valley and along Boston’s Route 128. As she explains, the culture of work and the resulting firm structures in Silicon Valley differed significantly from those in Boston, giving it critical advantages to become the preeminent region of technology development.
Even in the early days of the 1950s and 1960s, the West Coast had a far more open and decentralized network of employees, which contributed to intense knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value As a Result of Pricing Mobile Data Use</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 19:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</guid>
      <description>I was reading over the comments my former colleagues at the International Center for Law and Economics and TechFreedom filed on Title II reclassification to find these two paragraphs of pure Alchian bliss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information wants to be expensive as well as free</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</guid>
      <description>Famously, Stewart Brand noted that “information wants to be free.” But, that statement leaves off the other half of the phrase, thus burying the complexity of his thinking. In an email, he explained,
He continues in his book, “The MIT Media Lab”:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Policy Becomes a Battleground for Lifestyles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 20:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ quotes a section of Richard Wagner ’s “Economic Policy in a Liberal Democracy” (1996):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Economic Environment Will TV Unbundling Create?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 22:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</guid>
      <description>The Technology Policy Institute just went live with a video of their OTT event, exploring TV unbundling. There is a lot of solid material, but Laura Martin, a Senior Analyst at Needham &amp;amp; Company, explained what would happen if we went to an unbundled world:
 As soon as you unbundle, you lose advertising revenue. Immediately, you have to double the cost because of lost ad dollars. 1/2 of the revenues come from ads and the other 1/2 comes from subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola Responses &amp; Institutional Differences</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/ebola-responses-institutional-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 16:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/ebola-responses-institutional-differences/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation, Robot Economics &amp; Employment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</guid>
      <description>David Autor just released a new paper exploring the intellectual development and paradoxes in machine displacement of labor. The paper is especially timely given the broad discussion of labor markets economics is having post downturn.
It begins with a quote from the better of Polanyi brothers, Michael, who observed, “We can know more than we can tell… The skill of a driver cannot be replaced by a thorough schooling in the theory of the motorcar; the knowledge I have of my own body differs altogether from the knowledge of its physiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (Robot) Revolution Will be Televised</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 21:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</guid>
      <description>A lot of stories about robot economics have popped up in the past couple weeks. Here is a couple of the most interesting:
 Human Needs Not Apply (Video) AI, Robotics, and the Future of Jobs from Pew Should your robot driver kill you to save a child’s life? As machines take on more human work, what’s left for us? from Pew  And for those who are interested, there is a blog dedicated to robot economics, called appropriately enough RobotEconomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in the 1700s Was Very Poor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</guid>
      <description>The natural state of humanity is poverty, not abundance. Poor, nasty brutish and short was the way of life for nearly until 250 years ago, especially poor. Here was life in the early 1700s, for example:
 Every item of clothing was made by hand to fit the consumer. Suits made like this today costs around $4,000. Consider affording that on subsistence wages.  In France, it was common for poor laborers to not wear shoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought Lecture 1 and 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been watching Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought class on YouTube for a refresher on the subject. Here are my notes:
  Probably the most important part for the creation of the modern state is the creation of a unified market. True, the places that did open up to trade first were the Italian city states, but soon after the Dutch began to create cost-less trade networks, and then followed England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Joel Mokyr’s Lever of Riches</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 16:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</guid>
      <description>Economic growth can happen in one of four ways: 1) Solovian growth where capital accumulation occurs at a faster rate than growth of the labor force so each worker has more capital to work with, 2) Smithian growth where there is increase in trade, 3) Scale or sizing effects, or 4) Schumpeterian growth, that is, capitalist expansion deriving from continuous though fluctuating, technological change and innovation financed through the extension of credit Economists typically approach the explanation of technological change by considering the relationship between demand and supply variables, research and development and productivity growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grab for the Graph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</guid>
      <description>Connecting search with social would be a huge step to completing the social graph. Currently Facebook has the lead on this one, but if Google is able to sidestep the privacy issues, which have been thorny, they could capture the pie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of Google</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</guid>
      <description>Via Eli Dourado, this deserves to be quoted in full:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Foolishness of Jonathan Chait</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</guid>
      <description>Talking about financial reform, Jonathan Chait over at TNR lamented the lack of knowledge within liberal circles on how to move forward. As he says,
The belief that any regulation could prevent the next crisis is foolish. Like clockwork, there has been an economic downturn every ten years for the last 400 years, at least. Even though he is not willing to come right out and say it, Chait does seem to admit the futility of tough regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and iAd</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</guid>
      <description>I really don’t know how this went past me, but I was watching Fast Money today and Kaminsky made note of Apple going into direct search. To make this a little more solid, look at this,
The always insightful Picard makes this more tangible:
Only time will allow us to understand how this is going to work out, but regardless, it is an interesting time to be in media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tony Judt is wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>I just read a new essay from Tony Judt he wrote in the New York Times Book Review. For me, the takeaway part was the very beginning where he said,
Later, he laments, saying,
With the worst of the economic crisis behind us, social commentators like Judt are calling for action, demanding that leaders and society change to advert another economic crisis. Sadly, this is yet another lofty aspiration based on fallacious Enlightenment ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
