<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sociology &amp;amp; Psychology on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/sociology-amp-psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sociology &amp;amp; Psychology on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 18:10:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/sociology-amp-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Vindication Of Classical Rhetoric Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/vindication-power-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 18:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/vindication-power-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Pain might actually have a pro-social function:
Students of rhetoric might have already suspected that, however. Pathos, one of the traditional appeals set down by Aristotle, is usually translated as emotional appeal. But ancient Greek was a preliterate language that conserved words by attaching multiple meanings onto them. This helps to explain why arete is such an expansive term. Accordingly, pathos meant both to suffer and to experience. In a small way, this study supports this ancient line of thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Paradoxes Of Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>Svetlana Boym has a fascinating article on nostalgia. Here are some choice parts:
Interesting essay throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Technological / Cultural Determinism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 03:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</guid>
      <description>Alex Parrish begins “Adaptive Rhetoric: Evolution, Culture, and the Art of Persuasion” by recalling a story about one reaction to his book, and in doing so, helps to explain the problem of the technological/cultural determinism debate:
Parrish is right. The either/or presentation of culture and biology leads us to believe that one must take precedent in guiding behavior. The same kind of criticism can be heaped on the technological/cultural determinist deabate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Technology, the Past is No Longer a Foreign Country</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</guid>
      <description>Novelist L. P. Hartley once wrote, “The past is a foreign country: they do things differently there.” Ironically, we may no longer live in his world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Famous Psychological Experiment Has Serious Flaws</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 20:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</guid>
      <description>As you might recall, the Stanford Prison Experiment pitted several student against each other as randomly chosen prison guards or prisoners. The end result was quite gruesome. Guards enforced authoritarian measures and even inflicted psychological torture on the prisoners. The experiment is a classic note in psychology texts and has often been used to explain the Nazis, Abu Ghraib, and other forms of inhumane practices.
Apparently, there are serious flaws with the study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulf Between Libertarians and Other Social Theorists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know why I have never considered it before, but Ross Kenyon is correct:
Methodologically, libertarians and Austrians see the world largely as aggregated individuals, compared to other social theorists who mainly consider the world through group level dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multistakeholder Meeting Illuminates Various Problems of Objectivity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>At the NTIA Multistakeholder Meeting this week, it was suggested that all those studies submitted and funded by an outside source be disclosed. Later, when the issue of objectivity came up again, it was suggested that the group should rely on professors to provide objective views. While I am for disclosure in practice and not necessarily against the academy, both of the suggestions belie a flawed, but pervasive, vision on the connection between objectivity and research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conflict of Visions Does Not Align Well With Parties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</guid>
      <description>Charles Murray’s review of Thomas Sowell’s “A Conflict of Visions: Ideological Origins of Political Struggles” begins:
While I tend to think Sowell’s thesis explains a lot for the libertarian/non-libertarian divide, it is not so clear that the left/right divide aligns as well. Both parties use the government to enact their preferred area of concern. It just happens that the traditional Right tends to concern itself with social issues while the Left does so with economic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Great Sentences for Libertarians</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</guid>
      <description>From “Why Teaching Equality Hurts Men,”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Desmond Morris’ The Human Zoo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 04:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</guid>
      <description>What is surprising is that the bloated super-tribes have survived at all and, what is more, survived so well. This is not something we should accept simple because we are sitting here in the twentieth century, it is something we should marvel at. It is an astonishing testimony to our incredible ingenuity, tenacity and plasticity as a species. How on earth did we manage it? If our hunting ancestors had really been ruthless, greedy tyrants, loaded with ‘original sin’, the human success story would have petered out long ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Postmodernism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</guid>
      <description>The opening to “The End of Sociological Theory” by Steven Seidman:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Quotes on ‘The Foucault Effect: Studies in Governmentality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 22:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks, I have been become fascinated with the the history of policing, an area of dire import for libertarians of all stripes. Originally, the word police was synonymous with policy as we know it today e.g. civil administration, but slowly it began to take a different tact around the time when the modern state and economy were coming into their own. According to the etymology dictionary, the first force so-named in England was the Marine Police, set up 1798 to protect merchandise at the Port of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Profane</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 16:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fundamental distinctions in human thought is between the profane (profanum) and sacred (sacrum). Summarized by Nisbet,
The opposite of this is the profane, which is the utilitarian, individualistic world that we all inhabit. To see it another way, the profane revolves around the concerns of the individuals, while the sacred includes the concerns of the community. As Durkheim explained, people feel that the moral truths of the sacred are far more important than just personal preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 05:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</guid>
      <description>Rationality is only an instrument. It is a tool to achieving goals. Where do these goals come from? That is the better question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy and Freewill in a Previous Era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 02:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</guid>
      <description>For the pre-Socratic authors, tragedy was a very simple thing. Homer, being the bridge between the archaic and the ancient, exemplified this tragedy. Tragedy for this group was mankind going against fate. Tragedy was man’s betting of his own ability (hubris) against what the gods knew to be the future. This is why tragedy has been such a powerful story over the ages, I would argue. It taps into this very old, perhaps even subconscious belief that things in the world are ordered and thus determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasmussen, the FCC and Rape Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Adam Thierer over at Technology Liberation Front posted a Rasmussen poll that suggests,
He believes that it is due to FCC’s overreaching actions:
It is actually a little simpler than that. I don’t think many people know or even care about the FCC and Internet regulation. The story that broke this past week, which is probably the cause of this drop, more broadly fits into the concept of intrusion, which has been all the rage these past couple months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
