<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regulation on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/regulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regulation on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 16:50:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should the US Adopt the GDPR?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/should-the-us-adopt-the-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/should-the-us-adopt-the-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Last week, I had the honor of being a panelist at the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itif.org/events/2018/09/25/debate-should-us-copy-eu-privacy-law&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Information Technology and Innovation Foundation’s event&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;on the future of privacy regulation. The debate question was simple enough: Should the US copy the EU’s new privacy law? &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When we started planning the event, California’s Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) wasn’t a done deal. But now that it has passed and presents a deadline of 2020 for implementation, the terms of the privacy conversation have changed. Next year, 2019, Congress will have the opportunity to pass a law that could supersede the CCPA and some are looking to the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for guidance. Here are some reasons for not taking that path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Industries and the Telecom Sector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>The classical definition of competitive price are those where price equal cost. The thought being, if a producer pushes their price above this line, they will not be able to capture customers, and if they lower their prices, they will not be able to cover their cost. We often think of cost as the money one spend to produce an item, but it includes more; there is there also the cost of managing the firm, and importantly it includes the minimum level of profit the firm must return to be attractive to investors and thus have capital inflows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
