<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facebook on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facebook on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There are good reasons to be skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the threat of automation, I agree with Ryan Khurana: “From self-driving car crashes to failed workplace algorithms, many AI tools fail to perform simple tasks humans excel at, let alone far surpass us in every way.” Like myself, he is skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market, pointing out that “[The] conflation of what AI ‘may one day do’ with the much more mundane ‘what software can do today’ creates a powerful narrative around automation that accepts no refutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Kill Zone in Tech?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 22:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Noah Smith explored an emerging question in tech. Is there a kill zone where new and innovative upstarts are being throttled by the biggest players? He explains,
So, are American tech companies making it difficult for startups? Perhaps, but there are some other reasons to be skeptical.
First off, the nature of the venture capital market has changed due to the declining costs of computing. Not too long ago, much of a tech company’s Series A and B would be dedicated to buying server racks and computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did The Facebook Stock Drop Last Week? Some Economics Of Decision-making</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 22:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A curious thing happened last week. Facebook’s stock, which had seem to have weathered the 2018 controversies, took a beating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the Washington Post, Craig Timberg and Elizabeth Dwoskin &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/07/26/how-years-privacy-controversies-finally-caught-up-with-facebook/?utm_term=.33e4676e4d41&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;explained&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;that the stock market drop was representative of a larger wave:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jeff Chester of the Center for Digital Democracy piled on, describing the drop as “a privacy wake-up call that the markets are delivering to Mark Zuckerberg.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;But the downward pressure was driven by more fundamental changes. Simply put, Facebook missed its earnings target. But it is important to peer into why the company didn’t meet those targets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Online Public Sphere or: Facebook, Google, Reddit, and Twitter also support positive communities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In cleaning up my desk this weekend, I chanced upon an old notebook and like many times before I began to transcribe the notes. It was short, so I got to the end within a couple of minutes. The last page was scribbled with the German term Öffentlichkeit (public sphere), a couple sentences on Hannah Arendt, and a paragraph about Norberto Bobbio’s view of public and private. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Then I remembered. Yep. This is the missing notebook from a class on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zizi.people.uic.edu/Site/Courses_files/DemInDigAgeSyllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;democracy in the digital age&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.   &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Serendipitously, a couple of hours later, William Freeland alerted me to Franklin Foer’s newest piece in The Atlantic titled “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/07/the-death-of-the-public-square/564506/?utm_content=edit-promo&amp;amp;utm_campaign=the-atlantic&amp;amp;utm_term=2018-07-06T16%3A04%3A10&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Death of the Public Square&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.” Foer is the author of “World Without Mind: The Existential Threat of Big Tech,” and if you want a good take on that book, check out Adam Thierer’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reason.com/archives/2017/12/23/how-to-write-a-tech-panic-mani&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;review in Reason&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Much like the book, this Atlantic piece wades into techno ruin porn but focuses instead on the public sphere:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did The Supreme Court Get The Market Definition Correct In The Amex Case?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 20:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Supreme Court is winding down for the year and last week put out a much awaited decision in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-1454_5h26.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ohio v. American Express&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Some have rung the alarm with this case, but I think caution is worthwhile. In short, the Court’s analysis wasn’t expansive like some have claimed, but incomplete. There are a lot of important details to this case and the guideposts it has provided will likely be fought over in future litigation over platform regulation. To narrow the scope of this post, I am going to focus on the market definition question and the issue of two-sided platforms in light of the developments in the industrial organization (IO) literature in the past two decades.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
