<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:55:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What unknown technological invention will have a huge impact on the future? A compilation of Reddit answers.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/what-unknown-technological-invention-will-have-a-huge-impact-on-the-future-a-compilation-of-reddit-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/what-unknown-technological-invention-will-have-a-huge-impact-on-the-future-a-compilation-of-reddit-answers/</guid>
      <description>On Reddit, it was asked, what’s a relatively unknown technological invention that will have a huge impact on the future? As expected, there were countless great examples, so I compiled them below and tried to organize them by topic.
Biotechnology and medicine
 Microgel will be used to repair spines Research into bacteriophages could cure antibiotic resistant bacteria such as MRSA. Gene therapy will wildly proliferate. Wireless ECG machines will be more widely used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The most profound technologies are those that disappear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/the-most-profound-technologies-are-those-that-disappear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 19:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/the-most-profound-technologies-are-those-that-disappear/</guid>
      <description>A conversation today reminded me of the old Mark Weiser piece, which begins, “The most profound technologies are those that disappear.” It continues,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is reasoning inherently adversarial? Some random thoughts, unequally distributed</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/is-reasoning-inherently-adversarial-some-random-thoughts-unequally-distributed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/is-reasoning-inherently-adversarial-some-random-thoughts-unequally-distributed/</guid>
      <description>Is reasoning inherently adversarial? Some random thoughts, unequally distributed:
 From Gwern: In software engineering, rubber duck debugging is a method of debugging code. The name is a reference to a story in the book The Pragmatic Programmer in which a programmer would carry around a rubber duck and debug their code by forcing themselves to explain it, line-by-line, to the duck. Many other terms exist for this technique, often involving different (usually) inanimate objects, or pets such as a dog or a cat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhones may never be produced in the United States because of supply chain issues</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/iphones-may-never-be-produced-in-the-united-states-because-of-supply-chain-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 18:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/iphones-may-never-be-produced-in-the-united-states-because-of-supply-chain-issues/</guid>
      <description>This morning my friends Angel and Joseph asked for my help in arbitrating a dispute over a part of Michael Lind’s new book. The passage in question suggests that if the iPhone were completely manufactured in the United States, it would only cost an additional $100:

The original MIT Technology Review article on which the cite is taken also makes a similar kind of assumption. Chinese wages are lower and so they can make stuff much cheaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism and Breezewood</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/capitalism-and-breezewood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/capitalism-and-breezewood/</guid>
      <description>A vital question of our time springs from the noosphere:
Who knows of the sincerity of the post, but that’s Breezewood, PA. It’s a hellish place when I-70 comes to a grinding halt before it dumps into the Penna Turnpike. There should be a proper interchange between the two, and yet, Breezewood lives on as a series of red lights.
The place is a unique horror within the United States. “I’ve been everywhere except for North Dakota,” trucker Kevin Hendry told the Wall Street Journal in 1999.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making sense of content moderation, some foundations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/making-sense-of-content-moderation-some-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 22:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/making-sense-of-content-moderation-some-foundations/</guid>
      <description>To understand why content moderation and algorithmic choices at Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube are so loathed, it is important to understand a little psychology first.
Humans have a really bad habit of trying to make sense of the world. We see patterns where they don’t exist and grant intentionality where it shouldn’t be. There are lots of terms for it. Pareidolia, apophenia it is called. But it makes sense under error management theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zuboff’s “The Age of Surveillance Capitalism” raw notes and comments on the definition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/zuboffs-the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-raw-notes-and-comments-on-the-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/zuboffs-the-age-of-surveillance-capitalism-raw-notes-and-comments-on-the-definition/</guid>
      <description>Shoshana Zuboff’s book “The Age of Surveillance Capitalism” set a new tone in tech analysis since it was published in January of 2019. In just a year, her term, surveillance capitalism, has become a dominant mode of analysis. This year I am going to read the book and then post raw notes and comments on the book. What follows are my thoughts on the first part dealing with the definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years on, it is clear that the network neutrality fight was meta-miserable</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/two-years-on-it-is-clear-that-the-network-neutrality-fight-was-meta-miserable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/two-years-on-it-is-clear-that-the-network-neutrality-fight-was-meta-miserable/</guid>
      <description>Eric Weinstein’s recent conversation with Balaji Srinivasan reminded me of today’s auspicious anniversary. On this date, two years ago, the Restoring Internet Freedom Order took effect, effectively ending the Open Internet Order from the Obama Era.
Looking back, I can confidently say that the policy discussion surrounding network neutrality failed meta-miserably. Us policy wonks need to do better and a good first step would be the embrace of prediction tournaments and policy bets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of competition in telephony 1880-1900</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/a-brief-history-of-competition-in-telephany-1880-1900/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 16:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/a-brief-history-of-competition-in-telephany-1880-1900/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2017, Jonathan Taplin, made his case in the New York Times for breaking up Google by relating the early history of telephony:
 But, as Aswath Rao pointed out, the buildings of Boston were connected with a nest of wires in 1881 as well. Why is this specific picture important? Bell’s patents on the telephone expired in 1893, which sparked the independent revolution, so it was impossible for any competitor to exist before then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links Thursday, December 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/links-thursday-december-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 16:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/links-thursday-december-5/</guid>
      <description>More on tacit knowledge, this time from Samo Burja: “Before video became available at scale [through YouTube], tacit knowledge had to be transmitted in person, so that the learner could closely observe the knowledge in action and learn in real time — skilled metalworking, for example, is impossible to teach from a textbook. Because of this intensely local nature, it presents a uniquely strong succession problem: if a master woodworker fails to transmit his tacit knowledge to the few apprentices in his shop, the knowledge is lost forever, even if he’s written books about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call To Arms, or Antitrust Needs More Empirical Bayesian Research [Abstract]</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/a-call-to-arms-or-antitrust-needs-more-empirical-bayesian-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 16:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/a-call-to-arms-or-antitrust-needs-more-empirical-bayesian-research/</guid>
      <description>[Extended Abstract: November 1, 2019]
The mundane world of antitrust economics has been transformed in the last decade, driven by a recorded rise in economic concentration. Across the political range from President Trump and Senator Josh Hawley to presidential hopefuls Elizabeth Warren and Bernie Sanders, attention has been directed towards the largest and most malleable source of antitrust enforcement policy, merger policy. But like the rest of antitrust, there is a dearth of empirically rooted studies on the effectiveness of antitrust policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Entrepreneurial State, Some Brief Comments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-entrepreneurial-state-some-brief-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-entrepreneurial-state-some-brief-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economist Mariana Mazzucato has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/mariana-mazzucato?fbclid=IwAR2OPxV-MNLGWJpaCSivm35lD9xkKVcSfYNB0YxO-Q9qNv9hrAAmoruiNR0&#34;&gt;full spread in the Wired UK&lt;/a&gt; humbling suggesting that she “has a plan to fix capitalism.” The plan is an outgrowth of her 2013 book &lt;em&gt;The Entrepreneurial State&lt;/em&gt;, which contends that government involvement in research and development (R&amp;amp;D), loans, and other business subsidies are the true drivers of innovation, not the private sector. Her plan is simple: governments need to do better on funding innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that the government is massively involved in innovation and for good reason. Open any introductory economics text and you’re likely to see an argument for why. Private actors are short sighted and often fail to plan for the long term by investing in R&amp;amp;D that will lead to technological progress. Basic research also might lead to advances or products outside of the company’s niche. Knowing that they won’t be able to capture all of the gains from research, private entities will choose a lower level of investment than is optimal, leading to a market failure. Governments solve this market failure by allocating resources to expanding scientific and technological knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Mazzucato might be finding an audience with policy makers in the UK and doers in Silicon Valley, innovation economists are a little more wary of her state first theory of innovation. Here are some things worth considering when reading her work:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do You Value Data? A Reply To Jaron Lanier’s Op-Ed In The NYT</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/how-do-you-value-data-a-reply-to-jaron-laniers-op-ed-in-the-nyt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 21:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/how-do-you-value-data-a-reply-to-jaron-laniers-op-ed-in-the-nyt/</guid>
      <description>Jaron Lanier was featured in a recent New York Times op-ed explaining why people should get paid for their data. Under this scheme, he estimates the total value of data for a four person household could fetch around $20,000.
Let’s do the math on that.
Data from eMarketer finds that users spend about an hour and fifteen minutes per day on social media for a total of 456.25 hours per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links For Thursday, September 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/links-for-thursday-september-5-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 14:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/links-for-thursday-september-5-2019/</guid>
      <description>Will Oremus dissects that often repeated phrase, if you aren’t paying, you’re the product. While the piece is stellar, I don’t really agree with Oremus when he says that an alternative vision would “view ourselves as customers of Facebook, paying with our time, attention, and data instead of with money.” That assumes a payment system. Instead we should think of it as exchange. For better or worse, we still use the rhetoric of payments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Studies, Some Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>When I read through Patrick Collison and Tyler Cowen’s article in The Atlantic calling for a new science of progress that studies “successful people, organizations, institutions, policies, and cultures,” my first reaction was, yes of course, that needs to be done. And then the negative responses came in, minimizing the push from Collison and Cowen because, as the critics had argued, management theory and entrepreneurial studies and even history is doing the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An exploration of the limits of advertising byway of a brief review of the effects literature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/advertising-uneasy-persuasion-or-means-of-social-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/advertising-uneasy-persuasion-or-means-of-social-engineering/</guid>
      <description>[DRAFT: Monday, August 19, 2019]
The Domain Of The Critique
If you follow the major tech publications, you would think that the advertising of today is a powerful new weapon that desperately needs to be reigned in.
NYT technology reporter Natasha Singer laid it out, “What is at stake here isn’t privacy, the right not to be observed. It’s how companies can use our data to invisibly shunt us in directions that may benefit them more than us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studies Exploring GPS Adoption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/studies-exploring-gps-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 13:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/studies-exploring-gps-adoption/</guid>
      <description>I’m a couple of chapters into reading Re-Engineering Humanity from Brett Frischmann and Evan Selinger, which includes a discussion of the effects of GPS. So, I thought I would take a look at the literature. “Results showed that GPS users traveled longer distances and made more stops during the walk than map users and direct-experience participants. Also, GPS users traveled more slowly, made larger direction errors, drew sketch maps with poorer topological accuracy, and rated wayfinding tasks as more difficult than direct-experience participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ancien Regime of Newspapers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-ancien-regime-of-newspapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 14:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-ancien-regime-of-newspapers/</guid>
      <description>The newspaper business has become far more competitive in recent years, but not too long ago, most newspapers were flush with cash:
There is a lot more to the Atlantic piece, which you should check out, but the discussion reminds me of a Larry Downes’ piece from some time back on innovation, or lack thereof, at newspapers. As he says,
Of course there is variability in the marketplace, but it does seem like many newspapers had few problems keeping payroll in the period before the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Cost Estimation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/privacy-cost-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 19:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/privacy-cost-estimation/</guid>
      <description>This document is really just a proof of concept, but the basic idea is simple. I want to see how much data I can extract from a surveys on the cost of CCPA and GDPR from TrustArc. You can find details of that survey here.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are good reasons to be skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the threat of automation, I agree with Ryan Khurana: “From self-driving car crashes to failed workplace algorithms, many AI tools fail to perform simple tasks humans excel at, let alone far surpass us in every way.” Like myself, he is skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market, pointing out that “[The] conflation of what AI ‘may one day do’ with the much more mundane ‘what software can do today’ creates a powerful narrative around automation that accepts no refutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviving the Office of Technology Assessment would require a set of specific conditions in Congress. We have simply not arrived at that time.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/reviving-the-office-of-technology-assessment-would-require-a-set-of-specific-conditions-in-congress-we-have-simply-not-arrived-at-that-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 13:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/reviving-the-office-of-technology-assessment-would-require-a-set-of-specific-conditions-in-congress-we-have-simply-not-arrived-at-that-time/</guid>
      <description>Cato Unbound is taking on the issue of tech expertise this month and the lead essay came from Kevin Kosar, who argues for the revival of the Office of Technology Assessment. As he explains,
He continues, “Congress’s ineptitude in [science and technology policy] has been richly displayed.” To help embed expertise in science and technology policy, Kosar argues for the revival of the Office of Technology Assessment, which was established in 1972 and defunded in 1995.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural Broadband Isn’t Like Rural Electrification, It Is So Much Harder</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/rural-broadband-isnt-like-rural-electrification-it-is-so-much-harder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 20:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/rural-broadband-isnt-like-rural-electrification-it-is-so-much-harder/</guid>
      <description>Many have likened efforts to build out rural broadband today to the accomplishments of rural electrification in the 1930s. But the two couldn’t be further from each other. From the structure of the program and underlying costs, to the impact on productivity, rural electrification is drastically different than current efforts to get broadband in rural regions. My recent piece at ReaclClearPolicy explores some of those differences, but there is one area I wasn’t able to explore, the question of cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Esoteric Reading of LM Sacasas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</guid>
      <description>After reading LM Sacasas’ recent piece on moral communities, I couldn’t help but wonder if the piece was written in the esoteric mode.
Let me explain by some meandering.
Now, I am surely going to butcher his argument, so take a read of it yourself, but there is a bit of an interesting call and response structure to the piece. He begins with commentary on “frequent deployment of the rhetorical we,” in discussions over the morality of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kids Are Going To Be Alright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</guid>
      <description>Catchy headlines like “Heavy Social Media Use Linked With Mental Health Issues In Teens” and “Have Smartphones Destroyed a Generation?” advance a common trope of generational decline. But a new paper in Nature uses a new and rigorous analytical method to understand the relationship between adolescent well-being and digital technology, finding a “negative but small [link], explaining at most 0.4% of the variation in well-being.”
What really sets apart the new paper from Amy Orben and Andy Przybylski is that it aims to capture a more complete picture of how variables interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you’re worried about net neutrality, put your reputation on the line and make a prediction about the future</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/if-youre-worried-about-net-neutrality-put-your-reputation-on-the-line-and-make-a-prediction-about-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 14:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/if-youre-worried-about-net-neutrality-put-your-reputation-on-the-line-and-make-a-prediction-about-the-future/</guid>
      <description>It is now been a year since network neutrality rules supported by Title II were officially repealed, marking the end of the Obama-era legislation. Writing in Wired, Klint Finley noted that, “The good news is that the internet isn’t drastically different than it was before. But that’s also the bad news: The net wasn’t always so neutral to begin with.”
At the time, many worried what would happen. Apple co-founder Steve Wozniak and former FCC Commissioner Michael Copps suggested that two worlds were possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Short Responses To The Pacing Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</guid>
      <description>Contemporary tech criticism displays an anti-nostalgia. Instead of being reverent for the past, anxiety about the future abounds. In these visions, the future is imagined as a strange, foreign land, beset with problems. And yet, to quote that old adage, tomorrow is the visitor that is always coming but never arrives. The future never arrives because we are assembling it today.
The distance between the now and the future finds its hook in tech policy in the pacing problem, a term describing the mismatch between advancing technologies and society’s efforts to cope with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There a Kill Zone in Tech?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 22:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/is-there-a-kill-zone-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Noah Smith explored an emerging question in tech. Is there a kill zone where new and innovative upstarts are being throttled by the biggest players? He explains,
So, are American tech companies making it difficult for startups? Perhaps, but there are some other reasons to be skeptical.
First off, the nature of the venture capital market has changed due to the declining costs of computing. Not too long ago, much of a tech company’s Series A and B would be dedicated to buying server racks and computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Cathy O’Neil’s &#34;Weapons of Math Destruction&#34;</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/book-review-cathy-oneils-weapons-of-math-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/book-review-cathy-oneils-weapons-of-math-destruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To read Cathy O’Neil’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;(2016) is to experience another in a line of progressive pugilists of the technological age. Where Tim Wu took on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Future-Internet-How-Stop/dp/0300151241&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;the future of the Internet&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and Evgeny Morozov &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Net-Delusion-Dark-Internet-Freedom/dp/1610391063&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;chided online slactivism&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, O’Neil takes on algorithms, or what she has dubbed weapons of math destruction (WMD).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;O’Neil’s book came at just the right moment in 2016. It sounded the alarm about big data just as it was becoming a topic for public discussion. And now, two years later, her worries seem prescient. As she explains in the introduction,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;O’Neil is explicit about laying out the blame at the feet of the WMDs, “You cannot appeal to a WMD. That’s part of their fearsome power. They do not listen.” Yet, these models aren’t deployed and adopted in a frictionless environment. Instead, they “reflect goals and ideology” as O’Neil readily admits. Where &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;falters is that it ascribes too much agency to algorithms in places, and in doing so misses the broader politics behind algorithmic decision making.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should The New NPR Poll On Rural America Make You Reconsider Your View of Rural Broadband Development?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/should-the-new-npr-poll-on-rural-america-make-you-reconsider-your-view-of-rural-broadband-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/should-the-new-npr-poll-on-rural-america-make-you-reconsider-your-view-of-rural-broadband-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;National Public Radio, the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, and the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health just published a new report on “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/HARVARD-POLL/rural-health-poll-10-15-18-updated.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Life in Rural America&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.” This survey of 1,300 adults living in the rural United States has a lot to say about health issues, population change, the strengths and challenges for rural communities, as well as discrimination and drug use. But I wanted to highlight two questions related to rural broadband development that might make you update your beliefs about massive rural investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Techno-optimism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/in-defense-of-techno-optimism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 18:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/in-defense-of-techno-optimism/</guid>
      <description>Many are understandably pessimistic about platforms and technology. This year has been a tough one, from Cambridge Analytica and Russian trolls to the implementation of GDPR and data breaches galore.
Those who think about the world, about the problems that we see every day, and about their own place in it, will quickly realize the immense frailty of humankind. Fear and worry makes sense. We are flawed, each one of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should the US Adopt the GDPR?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/should-the-us-adopt-the-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 16:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/should-the-us-adopt-the-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Last week, I had the honor of being a panelist at the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itif.org/events/2018/09/25/debate-should-us-copy-eu-privacy-law&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Information Technology and Innovation Foundation’s event&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;on the future of privacy regulation. The debate question was simple enough: Should the US copy the EU’s new privacy law? &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;When we started planning the event, California’s Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) wasn’t a done deal. But now that it has passed and presents a deadline of 2020 for implementation, the terms of the privacy conversation have changed. Next year, 2019, Congress will have the opportunity to pass a law that could supersede the CCPA and some are looking to the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for guidance. Here are some reasons for not taking that path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Facebook Now Over-moderating Content?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/is-facebook-now-over-moderating-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/is-facebook-now-over-moderating-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Reading professor Siva Vaidhyanathan’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/05/opinion/facebook-sandberg-congress.html&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;recent op-ed&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;in the New York Times, one could reasonably assume that Facebook is now seriously tackling the enormous problem of dangerous information. In detailing his takeaways from a recent hearing with Facebook’s COO Sheryl Sandberg and Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey, Vaidhyanathan explained,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;But it could be that, in their zeal to trapple down criticism from all sides, Facebook instead has corrected too far and is now over-moderating. The fundamental problem is that it is nearly impossible to know the true amount of disinformation on a platform. For one, there is little agreement on what kind of content needs to be policed. It is doubtful everyone would agree what constitutes fake news and separates it from disinformation or propaganda and how all of that differs from hate speech. But more fundamentally, even if everyone agreed to what should be taken down, it is still not clear that algorithmic filtering methods would be able to perfectly approximate that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Should Privacy Be Defined? A Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/how-should-privacy-be-defined-a-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/how-should-privacy-be-defined-a-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Privacy is an &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Essentially_contested_concept&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;essentially contested concept&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. It evades a clear definition and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1980849&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;when it is defined&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, scholars do so inconsistently. So, what are we to do now with this fractured term? Ryan Hagemann suggests a bottom up approach. Instead of beginning from definitions, we should be building a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://niskanencenter.org/blog/think-privacy-matters/&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;folksonomy of privacy harms&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Hagemann aims to route around definitional problems by exploring the spaces where our interests intersect with the concept of privacy, in our relations to government, to private firms, and to other people. It is a subtle but important shift in outlook that is worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Technology Matters For Tech Policy And Growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dan Wang has &lt;a href=&#34;https://danwang.co/how-technology-grows/&#34;&gt;a new post&lt;/a&gt; titled “How Technology Grows (a restatement of definite optimism)” and it is characteristically good. For tech policy wonks and policymakers, put it in your queue. The essay clocks in at 7500 words, but there’s a lot to glean from the piece. Indeed, he puts into words a number of ideas I’ve been wanting to write about. To set the stage, he begins first by defining what we mean by technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he rightly points out, the United States has, for various reasons, set aside the focus on process knowledge. Where this is especially evident comes in our manufacturing base:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/blog/us-needs-more-manufactured-exports&#34;&gt;an outlier among&lt;/a&gt; rich countries when it comes to manufacturing exports. It needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did The Facebook Stock Drop Last Week? Some Economics Of Decision-making</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 22:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A curious thing happened last week. Facebook’s stock, which had seem to have weathered the 2018 controversies, took a beating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the Washington Post, Craig Timberg and Elizabeth Dwoskin &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/07/26/how-years-privacy-controversies-finally-caught-up-with-facebook/?utm_term=.33e4676e4d41&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;explained&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;that the stock market drop was representative of a larger wave:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jeff Chester of the Center for Digital Democracy piled on, describing the drop as “a privacy wake-up call that the markets are delivering to Mark Zuckerberg.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;But the downward pressure was driven by more fundamental changes. Simply put, Facebook missed its earnings target. But it is important to peer into why the company didn’t meet those targets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Online Public Sphere or: Facebook, Google, Reddit, and Twitter also support positive communities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In cleaning up my desk this weekend, I chanced upon an old notebook and like many times before I began to transcribe the notes. It was short, so I got to the end within a couple of minutes. The last page was scribbled with the German term Öffentlichkeit (public sphere), a couple sentences on Hannah Arendt, and a paragraph about Norberto Bobbio’s view of public and private. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Then I remembered. Yep. This is the missing notebook from a class on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zizi.people.uic.edu/Site/Courses_files/DemInDigAgeSyllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;democracy in the digital age&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.   &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Serendipitously, a couple of hours later, William Freeland alerted me to Franklin Foer’s newest piece in The Atlantic titled “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/07/the-death-of-the-public-square/564506/?utm_content=edit-promo&amp;amp;utm_campaign=the-atlantic&amp;amp;utm_term=2018-07-06T16%3A04%3A10&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Death of the Public Square&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.” Foer is the author of “World Without Mind: The Existential Threat of Big Tech,” and if you want a good take on that book, check out Adam Thierer’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reason.com/archives/2017/12/23/how-to-write-a-tech-panic-mani&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;review in Reason&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Much like the book, this Atlantic piece wades into techno ruin porn but focuses instead on the public sphere:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did The Supreme Court Get The Market Definition Correct In The Amex Case?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 20:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/did-the-amex-case-get-the-market-definition-correct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Supreme Court is winding down for the year and last week put out a much awaited decision in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-1454_5h26.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ohio v. American Express&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Some have rung the alarm with this case, but I think caution is worthwhile. In short, the Court’s analysis wasn’t expansive like some have claimed, but incomplete. There are a lot of important details to this case and the guideposts it has provided will likely be fought over in future litigation over platform regulation. To narrow the scope of this post, I am going to focus on the market definition question and the issue of two-sided platforms in light of the developments in the industrial organization (IO) literature in the past two decades.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learn From Past Government-Imposed Corporate Breakups Is That They Don&#39;t Work</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/what-we-learn-from-past-government-imposed-corporate-breakups-is-that-they-dont-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 18:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/what-we-learn-from-past-government-imposed-corporate-breakups-is-that-they-dont-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Voices from all over the political and professional spectrum have been clamoring for tech companies to be broken up. T&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ech investor &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/02/15/roger-mcnamee-google-should-be-broken-up-into-8-companies.html&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Roger McNamee,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;machine learning pioneer Yoshua Bengio&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axios.com/the-case-for-breaking-up-big-tech-1516625369-8695e00f-4e82-4ba1-ae89-abcd17e2a1ee.html&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;NYU professor Scott Galloway&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Marco Rubio’s 2016 presidential digital director&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; have all suggested that tech companies should be forcibly separated. So,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; I took a look at some of the past efforts in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanactionforum.org/insight/a-history-of-failure-government-imposed-corporate-breakups/&#34;&gt;new survey of corporate breakups&lt;/a&gt; and found that they really weren’t all that effective at creating competitive markets.&lt;br&gt;
Although many consider &lt;em&gt;Standard Oil&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/em&gt; as classic cases, I think &lt;em&gt;United States v. American Tobacco Company&lt;/em&gt; is far more instructive. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Roundup of Commentary on the Supreme Court&#39;s Carpenter v. United States Decision</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/a-roundup-of-commentary-on-the-supreme-courts-carpenter-v-united-states-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 13:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/a-roundup-of-commentary-on-the-supreme-courts-carpenter-v-united-states-decision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, the Supreme Court ruled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-402_h315.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carpenter v.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;United&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;States&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a case involving the cell-site location information. In the 5 to 4 decision, the Court declared that “The Government’s acquisition of Carpenter’s cell-site records was a Fourth Amendment search.” What follows below is a roundup of reactions and comments to the decision. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Roundup of Reactions to the Supreme Court&#39;s Decision for Online Sales Tax</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/a-roundup-of-reactions-to-the-supreme-courts-decision-for-online-sales-tax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 17:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/a-roundup-of-reactions-to-the-supreme-courts-decision-for-online-sales-tax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Supreme Court dropped &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/17-494_j4el.pdf&#34;&gt;a decision&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Wayfair v. South Dakota&lt;/em&gt;, a case on the issue of online sales tax. As always, the holding is key: “Because the physical presence rule of &lt;em&gt;Quill&lt;/em&gt; is unsound and incorrect, &lt;em&gt;Quill Corp. v. North Dakota&lt;/em&gt;, 504 U. S. 298, and &lt;em&gt;National Bellas Hess, Inc. v. Department of Revenue of Ill.&lt;/em&gt;, 386 U. S. 753, are overruled.” What follows below is a roundup of reactions and comments to the decision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandating AI Fairness May Come At The Expense Of Other Types of Fairness</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/mandating-ai-fairness-may-come-at-the-expense-of-other-types-of-fairness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 18:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/mandating-ai-fairness-may-come-at-the-expense-of-other-types-of-fairness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, ProPublica &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing&#34;&gt;initiated a conversation&lt;/a&gt; over the use of risk assessment algorithms when they concluded that a widely used “score proved remarkably unreliable in forecasting violent crime” in Florida. Their examination of the racial disparities in scoring has been cited countless times, often as a proxy for the power of automation and algorithms in daily life. Indeed, as the authors concluded, these scores are “part of a part of a larger examination of the powerful, largely hidden effect of algorithms in American life.”&lt;br&gt;
As this examination continues, two precepts are worth keeping in mind. First, the social significance of algorithms needs to be considered, not just their internal model significance. While the accuracy of algorithms are important, more emphasis should be placed on how they are used within institutional settings. And second, fairness is not a single idea. Mandates for certain kinds of fairness could come at the expense of others forms of fairness. As always, policymakers need to be cognizant of the trade offs.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia As An Activist State</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2017/russia-as-an-activist-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 21:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2017/russia-as-an-activist-state/</guid>
      <description>The evidence is building:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ILECs, the Other Fiber Provider</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2017/ilecs-the-other-fiber-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 14:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2017/ilecs-the-other-fiber-provider/</guid>
      <description>This map comes via Doug Dawson, who details the ILEC fiber network:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Is Music Worth?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/how-much-is-music-worth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 13:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/how-much-is-music-worth/</guid>
      <description>Pitchfork has a great article on the consumer prices of music over the last century. Some interesting bits:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Legal Advisories on the New Net Neutrality Rules</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>The new network neutrality rules have been out for almost a month now. Here is a short collection of legal opinions:
 “Net Neutrality V.3: What We Know So Far” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “A First Look Inside the Net Neutrality Order” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “The FCC’s Open Internet Order: New Net Neutrality Rules and Title II Regulation of Broadband” by Bennett L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into the Regulation Market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</guid>
      <description>In response to the new Tyler Cowen and Alex Alex Tabarrok piece on information asymmetry, Arnold Kling wonders if:
My response:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demand Led Growth in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/demand-led-growth-in-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/demand-led-growth-in-social-media/</guid>
      <description>One part of this intriguing interview with the creator of the Medieval Reactions Twitter account really caught my eye:
Demand led content growth is a scary new world for content creators, one that really makes the old guard feel uneasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why It’s Important That The Internet Created Technopopulism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</guid>
      <description>After finishing ITIF’s new report on technopopulism, I couldn’t help but think, isn’t this missing a couple of pages, about, you know, the Internet?
While there is much to like about the report, the missing piece, the missing message, as McLuhan famously quipped, is the medium.
Here is the basic gist of the report. In the old days, tech policy was decided by educated wonks who knew the finer points of policy and could make reasoned arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whence Shall Innovation Come? A Rejoinder to Jacobin’s Red Innovation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whence-shall-innovation-come-a-rejoinder-to-jacobin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 15:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whence-shall-innovation-come-a-rejoinder-to-jacobin/</guid>
      <description>This month’s Jacobin Magazine tackles the subject of technology, and in it, one article titled “Red Innovation” was an interesting read, but it displays the countless pitfalls of thinkers who are not trained in economics but proffer on capitalism. Here is one section:
And yet, if Apple had not developed those products for the masses then they would simply be nice ideas in the pages of some fraying journal. Production is one side of the market of which research is a part; markets also include consumption, interestingly enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political Principal-Agent Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/the-political-principal-agent-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 19:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/the-political-principal-agent-problem/</guid>
      <description>This headline came across my Twitter feed today: “As Fairfax grows more diverse, candidates for office mostly don’t.” Immediately I thought of the principal-agent problem. Here is one bit:
This actually leads to some interesting questions. Does the inclusion of legislative agents that are more ethnically representative of principals ensure more representative outcomes? In other words, does the Republican Party need to incorporate more diversity in their legislative pool to ensure a broadening of the issues?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meritocracy in Blogging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/meritocracy-in-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 14:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/meritocracy-in-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Stories like this really push back against the filter bubble thesis:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law As a Performance of Ideological Assumptions</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/law-performance-ideological-assumptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 23:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/law-performance-ideological-assumptions/</guid>
      <description>From a paper on the 1926 Radio Act:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Competition in Network Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Alissa Cooper, formerly at CDT and now at Cisco, wrote her PhD dissertation on network neutrality practices in the US and the UK. Here is an interesting tidbit from her abstract:
In many European countries, unbundling has lead to competition among providers. While this has put downward pressure on consumer prices, investment in the backbone is far lower. Altogether, these industry features often lead companies pricing data since their margins are low, thus leading to very schemes that network neutrality advocates deplore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jefferson’s Contractual Society</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/jeffersons-contractual-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 04:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/jeffersons-contractual-society/</guid>
      <description>When Jefferson said “The earth belongs to the living,” he was railing against the popular Burkean revision of Locke’s contractual society.
The quote comes from a letter to Madison and makes sense only in the broader debate between Burke and Paine:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Tastes in the Top 40 &amp; Some Economics of Music</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 15:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</guid>
      <description>A back and forth has popped up about the Top 40. It began with Libby Jacobson comparing a Top 40 list from 1996 and today. As she points out, even though only Alanis Morissette was the only one to have two songs in the Top 40, today the Top 40 shows much less variety:
Ultimately, Jacobson concludes that “pop music is converging both in terms of style/sound and in terms of the talent &amp;amp; personalities producing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micropayments, The News, &amp; Friction Free Browsing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 19:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week I heard Walter Isaacson delve into his new book, “The Innovators,” at the American Enterprise Institute. In discussion, he lamented the development of the various business models in online journalism, and content generally, arguing forcefully for micropayments in their place. In a LinkedIn article on the same subject, he explains:
Even though I am not in the prediction business, I am highly skeptical that micropayments will become widespread for a number of reasons, none of which are particularly new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill Profiles Gigi Sohn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</guid>
      <description>Julian Hattem has a profile of Gigi Sohn, charting her influence over the network neutrality debate. The former head of an advocacy organization now leads from the inside:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s The FCC’s Rush on New Net Neutrality Rules?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>Network neutrality rules have failed to pass Congress and the courts countless times, so what’s the FCC’s rush now? Scott Cleland explores in an op-ed at the Daily Caller:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats on the NYPD Work Stoppage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/stats-nypd-work-stoppage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 17:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/stats-nypd-work-stoppage/</guid>
      <description>In reaction to what NYPD’s Police Benevolent Association chief Patrick Lynch calls a “hostile anti-police environment in the city,” officers are simply refusing to arrest or ticket people for minor offenses, leading to an overall arrest dropoff of nearly 66 percent.
Matt Taibbi explains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics of Euvoluntary Exchange</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samuel Wilson’s prodigious and interesting output at &lt;a href=&#34;http://euvoluntaryexchange.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary Exchange&lt;/a&gt; lead me to two articles by Michael Munger, the source of the blog’s name and focus. The first article “&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.duke.edu/~munger/euvol.pdf&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary or Not, Exchange is Just&lt;/a&gt;” is fascinating. Here is the main thesis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Munger, euvoluntary exchange is the name given to any any truly voluntary exchange that leaves both parties better off than before. To be truly voluntary or euvoluntary, the exchange requires&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Genesis of the Career Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 16:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>I have begun in earnest to read through Annalee Saxenian’s “Regional Advantage,” charting the computer industry’s genesis in both Silicon Valley and along Boston’s Route 128. As she explains, the culture of work and the resulting firm structures in Silicon Valley differed significantly from those in Boston, giving it critical advantages to become the preeminent region of technology development.
Even in the early days of the 1950s and 1960s, the West Coast had a far more open and decentralized network of employees, which contributed to intense knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value As a Result of Pricing Mobile Data Use</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 19:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</guid>
      <description>I was reading over the comments my former colleagues at the International Center for Law and Economics and TechFreedom filed on Title II reclassification to find these two paragraphs of pure Alchian bliss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information wants to be expensive as well as free</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</guid>
      <description>Famously, Stewart Brand noted that “information wants to be free.” But, that statement leaves off the other half of the phrase, thus burying the complexity of his thinking. In an email, he explained,
He continues in his book, “The MIT Media Lab”:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Policy Becomes a Battleground for Lifestyles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 20:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ quotes a section of Richard Wagner ’s “Economic Policy in a Liberal Democracy” (1996):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Economic Environment Will TV Unbundling Create?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 22:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</guid>
      <description>The Technology Policy Institute just went live with a video of their OTT event, exploring TV unbundling. There is a lot of solid material, but Laura Martin, a Senior Analyst at Needham &amp;amp; Company, explained what would happen if we went to an unbundled world:
 As soon as you unbundle, you lose advertising revenue. Immediately, you have to double the cost because of lost ad dollars. 1/2 of the revenues come from ads and the other 1/2 comes from subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Eli Pariser’s “The Filter Bubble: What the Internet Is Hiding from You”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 20:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“To my preteen self, it seemed clear that the Internet was going to democratize the world, connecting us with better information and the power to act on it. The California futurists and techno-optimists in those pages spoke with a clear-eyed certainty; an inevitable, irresistible revolution was just around the corner, one that would flatten society, unseat the elites, and usher in a kind of freewheeling global utopia.” pg 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Filter Bubble introduces three dynamics we’ve never dealt with before: first, you are alone in it, as it is you own personal bubble. Second, it is invisible in its actions. Finally, you don’t choose to enter into the bubble. pp 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the cost of communication over large distances and to large groups of people has plummeted, we’re increasingly unable to attend to it all,” leading to what blogger and media analyst Steve Rubel calls the attention crash. p 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of personalization is appealing as a “return to a Ptolemaic universe in which the sun and everything else revolves around us.” p 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the filter bubble, there’s less room for the chance encounters that bring insight and learning” p 15 My reaction: &lt;em&gt;What does Kirzner have to say about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be the author of your life, professor Yochai Benkler argues, you have to be aware of a diverse array of options and lifestyles. When you enter a filter bubble, you’re letting companies that construct it choose which options you’re aware of. You may think that you’re the captain of your own destiny, but personalization can lead you down a road to a kind of informational determinism in which what you’ve clicked on in the past determines what you see next—a Web history you’re doomed to repeat.” p 16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Putnam defined two kinds of social capital: in-group oriented bonding capital represents those events when you meet an old friend, while bridging capital occurs when lots of people from different backgrounds come together to meet each other, like in a townhall. p 17&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Bill Maher / UC Berkeley Fiasco Really a Free Speech Issue, Or a Power Struggle?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/bill-maher-uc-berkeley-fiasco-really-free-speech-issue-power-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 02:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/bill-maher-uc-berkeley-fiasco-really-free-speech-issue-power-struggle/</guid>
      <description>David Frum has an intriguing post in The Atlantic dealing with the Bill Maher / UC Berkeley fiasco. Here are a couple of the choice paragraphs:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources on Digital Trade &amp; The Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/resources-digital-trade-transatlantic-trade-investment-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 15:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/resources-digital-trade-transatlantic-trade-investment-partnership/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to educate myself on digital goods, digital trade, and the Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership (TTIP). Here are some resources from that research:
 “Digital Trade in the U.S. and Global Economies” by United States International Trade Commission (Part 1, Part 2) “Digital Drag: Ranking 125 Nations by Taxes and Tariffs on ICT Goods and Services” by Ben Miller and Rob Atkinson at ITIF (source) “The Importance of the Internet and Transatlantic Data Flows for U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola Responses &amp; Institutional Differences</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/ebola-responses-institutional-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 16:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/ebola-responses-institutional-differences/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Vindication Of Classical Rhetoric Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/vindication-power-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 18:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/vindication-power-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Pain might actually have a pro-social function:
Students of rhetoric might have already suspected that, however. Pathos, one of the traditional appeals set down by Aristotle, is usually translated as emotional appeal. But ancient Greek was a preliterate language that conserved words by attaching multiple meanings onto them. This helps to explain why arete is such an expansive term. Accordingly, pathos meant both to suffer and to experience. In a small way, this study supports this ancient line of thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Paradoxes Of Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>Svetlana Boym has a fascinating article on nostalgia. Here are some choice parts:
Interesting essay throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Technological / Cultural Determinism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 03:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technological-cultural-determinist-distinction-bunk/</guid>
      <description>Alex Parrish begins “Adaptive Rhetoric: Evolution, Culture, and the Art of Persuasion” by recalling a story about one reaction to his book, and in doing so, helps to explain the problem of the technological/cultural determinism debate:
Parrish is right. The either/or presentation of culture and biology leads us to believe that one must take precedent in guiding behavior. The same kind of criticism can be heaped on the technological/cultural determinist deabate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stopping Easements Through Copyright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/stopping-easements-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/stopping-easements-copyright/</guid>
      <description>A Canadian artist, Peter von Tiesenhausen, has effectively stopped a pipeline through his 800 acre property by covering it with artwork and copyrighting the top six inches of his land as an artwork. Companies could gain use of his property through easements, but they are severely limited by the addition of a copyright. For lawyers and those who believe in property rights, easements are contentious.
Here is some more:
I am assuming they are in court, but I plan to read more about the claims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation, Robot Economics &amp; Employment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</guid>
      <description>David Autor just released a new paper exploring the intellectual development and paradoxes in machine displacement of labor. The paper is especially timely given the broad discussion of labor markets economics is having post downturn.
It begins with a quote from the better of Polanyi brothers, Michael, who observed, “We can know more than we can tell… The skill of a driver cannot be replaced by a thorough schooling in the theory of the motorcar; the knowledge I have of my own body differs altogether from the knowledge of its physiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (Robot) Revolution Will be Televised</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 21:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</guid>
      <description>A lot of stories about robot economics have popped up in the past couple weeks. Here is a couple of the most interesting:
 Human Needs Not Apply (Video) AI, Robotics, and the Future of Jobs from Pew Should your robot driver kill you to save a child’s life? As machines take on more human work, what’s left for us? from Pew  And for those who are interested, there is a blog dedicated to robot economics, called appropriately enough RobotEconomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Technology, the Past is No Longer a Foreign Country</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</guid>
      <description>Novelist L. P. Hartley once wrote, “The past is a foreign country: they do things differently there.” Ironically, we may no longer live in his world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is STELA the Vehicle for Video Reform?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/is-stela-the-vehicle-for-video-reform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 18:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/is-stela-the-vehicle-for-video-reform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though few things are getting passed this Congress, the pressure is on to reauthorize the Satellite Television Extension and Localism Act (STELA) before it expires at the end of this year. Unsurprisingly, many have hoped this “must pass bill” will be the vehicle for broader reform of video. Getting video law right is important for our content rich world, but the discussion needs to expand much further than STELA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommunication’s Regulatory Cat and Mouse Game</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Jon Henke has reviewed “The People’s Network: The Political Economy of the Telephone in the Gilded Age” for Reason. I haven’t read the book, but his take has placed it on the top of the list. As anyone who has read about the history of telecommunication regulation, policy formation is and has been a cat-and-mouse game between regulators and the regulated. Jon explains:
What can this history tell us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Famous Psychological Experiment Has Serious Flaws</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 20:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/famous-pyschological-experiment-has-serious-flaws/</guid>
      <description>As you might recall, the Stanford Prison Experiment pitted several student against each other as randomly chosen prison guards or prisoners. The end result was quite gruesome. Guards enforced authoritarian measures and even inflicted psychological torture on the prisoners. The experiment is a classic note in psychology texts and has often been used to explain the Nazis, Abu Ghraib, and other forms of inhumane practices.
Apparently, there are serious flaws with the study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks and the Proliferating Performances of Identity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/social-networks-and-the-proliferating-performances-of-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 02:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/social-networks-and-the-proliferating-performances-of-identity/</guid>
      <description>Tom Chatfield’s essay on technology and language groks Walter Ong and under-appreciated Medium theory. He begins at the genesis of the written word and makes a huge arc to today’s moral themes. First the problem of information scarcity:
Yet the world is now one of information abundance and mediums of exchange:
Leading to, among other things, new expressions of identity on the Internet:
Chatfield is right. The biggest gulf between digital natives and digital immigrants lies in the negotiation of an authentic social performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Undermines Prevailing Theory that Technology is Isolating</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</guid>
      <description>An ever-present theme in the commentary of modern technology is its isolating effect. Yet the truth is far more complex. This Boston Review article on technology points to a paper supported by the Annenberg School of Communication that seems to suggest we are becoming more social. By conducting a content analysis of films from four public spaces over a thirty-year period, the behavior and characteristics of 143,593 people were coded. A couple of key findings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demand Destruction Signals Long Term Shift in Energy Markets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/demand-destruction-signals-long-term-shift-in-energy-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 13:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/demand-destruction-signals-long-term-shift-in-energy-markets/</guid>
      <description>Recent estimates suggest the US might meet the Kyoto Protocol because of natural gas substitution. Slate is reporting on a related trend, energy demand destruction:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare.gov &amp; the Scalability Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/healthcare-gov-the-scalability-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 05:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/healthcare-gov-the-scalability-problem/</guid>
      <description>Scalability problems plague the creation of large web sites. This is especially poignant, given the Healthcare.gov web site fiasco:
Thus, it is not uncommon for large IT projects like this to have overrun costs or fail:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report Reiterates Axiom: Restrictive Spectrum Rules Unsuccessful</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/report-reiterates-axiom-restrictive-spectrum-rules-unsuccessful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 19:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/report-reiterates-axiom-restrictive-spectrum-rules-unsuccessful/</guid>
      <description>A report released today reiterates much of what we already know: restrictive spectrum rules aimed at achieving specific policy goals are mostly unsuccessful. I have previously written on this topic for the UK, which the report outlines in more detail, but both Canada and Germany have faced serious challenges and market distortions because of restrictive spectrum rules:
 In Germany, where regulators restricted participation in the 3G auction through spectrum caps, two new entrants withdrew from the market without deploying the newly acquired spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forget About Too Little Information or Too Much Information, Think About Search Costs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/forget-about-too-little-information-or-too-much-information-think-about-search-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 03:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/forget-about-too-little-information-or-too-much-information-think-about-search-costs/</guid>
      <description>Poking around Cory Doctrow’s Tumblr site today, I came across a Neil Gaiman quote:
From too little information to too much information in just a few short years? Presumably then, at some point there was a Goldilocks era when we had exactly the right amount of information. So, when exactly was that, 1998 or thereabouts? Gaiman’s rhetorical use of too much and too little information hardly makes sense when considered in finer detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frankenstein, the Modern Critical Horror Novel</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/frankenstein-the-modern-critical-horror-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 02:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/frankenstein-the-modern-critical-horror-novel/</guid>
      <description>An essay at the Times Literary Supplement adds context to Frankenstein:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Embodiment of Technopanics – Gesture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/the-embodiment-of-technopanics-gesture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 05:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/the-embodiment-of-technopanics-gesture/</guid>
      <description>The ability to point to something out there that we both do not see, is the key difference. It hints at something larger, at a more basic relationship between abstract gesture and abstract communication. There are however many of these threads running between anthropology, neuroscience, and psychology that paint a complex mosaic of relationships connecting language with important bodily features like gesture, motion, emotion and reason. The total project that has tried to draw together many of the important thought is generally being called cognitive science, and gives us an important theoretical underpinning to the power of technopanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“We are going to die, and that makes us the lucky ones…”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/we-are-going-to-die-and-that-makes-us-the-lucky-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 18:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/we-are-going-to-die-and-that-makes-us-the-lucky-ones/</guid>
      <description>“We are going to die, and that makes us the lucky ones. most people are never going to die because they are never going to be born. The potential people who could have been here in my place but who will in fact never see the light of day outnumber the sand grains of Sahara. Certainly those unborn ghosts include greater poets than Keats, scientists greater than Newton. We know this because the set of possible people allowed by our DNA so massively exceeds the set of actual people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TS Eliot’s “The Hollow Men”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/ts-eliots-the-hollow-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 20:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/ts-eliots-the-hollow-men/</guid>
      <description>The best parts of this poem come from the end:
Between the idea
And the reality
Between the motion
And the act
Falls the Shadow
Between the conception
And the creation
Between the emotion
And the response
Falls the Shadow
Between the desire
And the spasm
Between the potency
And the existence
Between the essence
And the descent
Falls the Shadow
For Thine is
Life is
For Thine is the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in the 1700s Was Very Poor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</guid>
      <description>The natural state of humanity is poverty, not abundance. Poor, nasty brutish and short was the way of life for nearly until 250 years ago, especially poor. Here was life in the early 1700s, for example:
 Every item of clothing was made by hand to fit the consumer. Suits made like this today costs around $4,000. Consider affording that on subsistence wages.  In France, it was common for poor laborers to not wear shoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEC Accuses the State of Illinois of Securities Fraud</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/sec-accuses-the-state-of-illinois-of-securities-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 18:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/sec-accuses-the-state-of-illinois-of-securities-fraud/</guid>
      <description>Yes, you read that title correctly. The NYT is reporting:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nuances of Neoliberalism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/the-nuances-of-neoliberalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 16:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/the-nuances-of-neoliberalism/</guid>
      <description>“Masters of the Universe” will be the next book in the pile, largely due to a review by Michael Clune:
I often find myself in discussions of neoliberalism and have implored others to consider a more detailed story of events, which this book seems to aim for. But Clune fails to mention the deregulation that occurred elsewhere in the economy, not just in monetary policy. Telecommunications, airlines and alcohol were all “deregulated,” the effect being lower prices and higher quality goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animals by Frank O’Hara</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/animals-by-frank-ohara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 20:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/animals-by-frank-ohara/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commiting to Individualism Means Identity Politics Must be Part of the Conversation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/if-there-is-a-commitment-to-individualism-in-libertarianism-then-identity-politics-must-be-part-of-the-conversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 17:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/if-there-is-a-commitment-to-individualism-in-libertarianism-then-identity-politics-must-be-part-of-the-conversation/</guid>
      <description>Over the last five years, the libertarian movement has expanded drastically. What was largely a niche group of individualist and anarchist radicals in the 1970s and 80s has been transformed in the last decade. Approval ratings for both of the parties have dropped as much as their views have grown apart. Bloated budgets, increased secularization and a distrust in governmental efficacy have furthered libertarian ideas.
But there is a bias in this growth, as Gina Luttrell points out,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Alchian Through His Ideas, or A Review of the Alchian-Allen Theorem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/remembering-alchian-through-his-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/remembering-alchian-through-his-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Armen Alchian passed away earlier this week and in reading some of the remembrances, I came across this review of the Alchian-Allen Theorem, which I have posted the pertinent parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Wage Laws Were Enacted To Ensure Institutional Racism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/minimum-wage-laws-were-enacted-to-ensure-institutional-racism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 17:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/minimum-wage-laws-were-enacted-to-ensure-institutional-racism/</guid>
      <description>A little known fact:
If that isn’t institutional racism, then I don’t know what is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Companies Do Not Maximize Profits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/companies-do-not-maximize-profits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 20:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/companies-do-not-maximize-profits/</guid>
      <description>Contrary to the popular sentiment, companies do not maximize profits. Armen Alchian explains:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Third of All Major Federal Rules Lack Notice-and-comment Procedures</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/a-third-of-all-major-federal-rules-lack-notice-and-comment-procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/a-third-of-all-major-federal-rules-lack-notice-and-comment-procedures/</guid>
      <description>In 2008 I voted for Barack Obama; it is unlikely I will ever vote again. Back then, I was enamored by the political change that could have been achieved with a “great man.” Like so many other features of my previously liberal disposition, this has become yet another vestige.
The State hasn’t changed all that much with Obama. As Susan Dudley notes,
In the year that separates Obama and Bush, there was a huge jump.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of Samsung’s Meteoric Rise</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/the-keys-to-samsungs-meteoric-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 18:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/the-keys-to-samsungs-meteoric-rise/</guid>
      <description>When Apple rebranded itself under the second reign of Steve Jobs, one of the pillars of company was the production of tightly integrated products. Famously, the first iteration of the iTunes phone, the Motorola Rokr, was despised by Jobs, forcing the company to vertical integrate into handset production.
As these things tend to happen, Samsung learned from Apple’s successes, built on them, and now the Korean company leads the mobile phone industry, though Apple is not far behind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between a Tax, a Fee, and a Penalty</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/the-difference-between-a-tax-a-fee-and-a-penalty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 17:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/the-difference-between-a-tax-a-fee-and-a-penalty/</guid>
      <description>The difference between a tax, a fee and a penalty is based on the purpose of the revenue.
 A tax is a levy collected for general government services. A fee is levy collected to provide a service that benefits the group of people from which the money is collected. A penalty is a levy collected with the express aim of deterring some kind of undesirable behavior.  As tax economist Scott Drenkard explained to me, “This distinction became especially important recently when Justice Roberts went against over a century of tax jurisprudence by declaring the individual mandate to be a tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAA Device Rules and the Continuing Problem of Spectrum Interference</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</guid>
      <description>This was bound to happen: the proliferation of mobile devices is beginning to cause the “incidents” involving airline passengers to rack up. From Nick Bilton:
At issue is the largely unproven idea that tablets and phones interfere with a plane’s computers and communication devices. But, the asymmetry in rules for flight and takeoff is especially peculiar. When electromagnetic interference does happen with mobile devices, it is usually limited to a narrowband of the spectrum, due to inadequate filtering, tuning, or poor frequency control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon &amp; Their Taxes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 21:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Reuters is reporting on the history and legal problems of Amazon’s taxes. Apparently, last year the IRS demanded $1.5 billion in back-taxes from “transfer pricing [of their] our foreign subsidiaries,” amounting to just under a tenth of their gross annual profit.
The article doesn’t take much knowledge of tax law to understand, but for the tl:dr crowd, here is the gist:
In 1999, Amazon began to bring foreign profits home from their French and British operations to balance the losses in the US, which at the time amounted to over $1 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Ways to Help Plan for the Future</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/7-ways-to-help-plan-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 04:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/7-ways-to-help-plan-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>From the World Future Society, here are methods to help predict and plan for the future:
 Systematically Scan the Media — Futurists often conduct ongoing and systematic surveys of news media and research institutes. These surveys help spot significant trends and technology breakthroughs. Futurists call this environmental scanning. Analyze and Extrapolate Trends — After the trends are identified, the next step is to plot the trends to show their direction and development into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gulf Between Libertarians and Other Social Theorists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-gulf-between-libertarians-and-other-social-theorists/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know why I have never considered it before, but Ross Kenyon is correct:
Methodologically, libertarians and Austrians see the world largely as aggregated individuals, compared to other social theorists who mainly consider the world through group level dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbert Spencer on the Right to Ignore the State</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 16:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/herbert-spencer-on-the-right-to-ignore-the-state/</guid>
      <description>From Social Statics:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inseparability of Rights and Duties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>On rights and duties by James Otteson:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Industry Innovates With Contracts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/solar-industry-innovates-with-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 17:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/solar-industry-innovates-with-contracts/</guid>
      <description>Innovative products are not necessarily followed by broad adoption. There needs be a business model behind it.
Lynee Kiesling over at Knowledge Problem has a post on the solar industry, which is interesting throughout. She cites a New York Times article which helps to explain part of the mystery of innovation:
And there you go. Deregulate the whole thicket of laws surrounding electricity, put residential customers on a payment plan and solar becomes a much more attractive investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought Lecture 1 and 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been watching Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought class on YouTube for a refresher on the subject. Here are my notes:
  Probably the most important part for the creation of the modern state is the creation of a unified market. True, the places that did open up to trade first were the Italian city states, but soon after the Dutch began to create cost-less trade networks, and then followed England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Technocrat?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/what-is-a-technocrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 20:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/what-is-a-technocrat/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was chatting with a friend of mine at the Tax Foundation and he made a bold claim—I was a technocrat.
At first, I was taken back. How could I ever be construed as a technocrat? I didn’t believe in technocracy at all. I asked him a couple of days later to define exactly what he meant and he said, “if you are having any constructive role in designing (implementing or suggesting the design) the specific institutional arrangement employed by the State, you are a technocrat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multistakeholder Meeting Illuminates Various Problems of Objectivity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>At the NTIA Multistakeholder Meeting this week, it was suggested that all those studies submitted and funded by an outside source be disclosed. Later, when the issue of objectivity came up again, it was suggested that the group should rely on professors to provide objective views. While I am for disclosure in practice and not necessarily against the academy, both of the suggestions belie a flawed, but pervasive, vision on the connection between objectivity and research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conflict of Visions Does Not Align Well With Parties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-conflict-of-visions-does-not-align-well-with-parties/</guid>
      <description>Charles Murray’s review of Thomas Sowell’s “A Conflict of Visions: Ideological Origins of Political Struggles” begins:
While I tend to think Sowell’s thesis explains a lot for the libertarian/non-libertarian divide, it is not so clear that the left/right divide aligns as well. Both parties use the government to enact their preferred area of concern. It just happens that the traditional Right tends to concern itself with social issues while the Left does so with economic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assorted Links</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/assorted-links-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 19:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/assorted-links-2/</guid>
      <description>This version of assorted links is dedicated to big data:
 Advances in Large Scale Computing at Google Trying to Keep Relevant with Search Means Baking in Big Data for Google The Algorithm that Runs the Innovation Economy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Great Sentences for Libertarians</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/some-great-sentences-for-libertarians/</guid>
      <description>From “Why Teaching Equality Hurts Men,”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Daniel Boorstin’s “The Republic of Technology”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>“An athlete of steel and iron with not a superfluous ounce of metal on it” exclaimed William Dean Howells when he recalled the gigantic 700-ton Corliss steam engine that towered over Machinery Hall at the Philadelphia International Exhibition. A festive crowd cheered as the engine set in motion a wonderful assortment of machines—pumping water, combing wool, spinning cotton, tearing hemp, printing newspapers, lithographing wallpaper, sewing cloth, folding envelopes, sawing logs, shaping wood, making shoes—8,000 machines spread over 13 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Richard Pipes’ “Property and Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>No society has ever existed without some kind of property, the vision of an ideal propertyless world must be grounded not in collective memory but in a collective longing. p 5
  Politics for those in The Republic were largely a matter of custom, not law. Hence for Plato, the ideal state would have no statutes. According to Plutarch, Lycurgus would not permit the rules he laid down for Sparta to be committed to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messianic Time</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/messianic-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 03:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/messianic-time/</guid>
      <description>Some possible evidence for messianic time from “The Classical Tradition” by Gilbert Highet—
 Romulus, Remus and two wolves (c. 800 B.C.?); the adoration of the Wise Men (A.D. 1); the capture of Jerusalem by the Romans (c. A.D. 70); the story of Weland and Beadogild (c. A.D. 400?); and an unknown myth, as well as an inscription about the whale itself    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Thomas P. Hughes “American Genesis”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 21:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</guid>
      <description>When more histories of technology that take the critical stance of the best histories of politics are written, American will realize that not only their remarkable achievements but many of their deep and persistent problems arise, in the name of order, system, and control, from the mechanization and systematization of life and from the sacrifice of the organic and the spontaneous p 4 As historian and social critic Lewis Mumford so eloquently insisted decades ago, technology is both shaper of, and is shaped by, values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Desmond Morris’ The Human Zoo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 04:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</guid>
      <description>What is surprising is that the bloated super-tribes have survived at all and, what is more, survived so well. This is not something we should accept simple because we are sitting here in the twentieth century, it is something we should marvel at. It is an astonishing testimony to our incredible ingenuity, tenacity and plasticity as a species. How on earth did we manage it? If our hunting ancestors had really been ruthless, greedy tyrants, loaded with ‘original sin’, the human success story would have petered out long ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Joel Mokyr’s Lever of Riches</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 16:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</guid>
      <description>Economic growth can happen in one of four ways: 1) Solovian growth where capital accumulation occurs at a faster rate than growth of the labor force so each worker has more capital to work with, 2) Smithian growth where there is increase in trade, 3) Scale or sizing effects, or 4) Schumpeterian growth, that is, capitalist expansion deriving from continuous though fluctuating, technological change and innovation financed through the extension of credit Economists typically approach the explanation of technological change by considering the relationship between demand and supply variables, research and development and productivity growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The police state began with the Inquisition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</guid>
      <description>This article, and the book that it is based on, seem hugely provocative:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Promise of Postmodernism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-promise-of-postmodernism/</guid>
      <description>The opening to “The End of Sociological Theory” by Steven Seidman:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Etymology of the word “Artifact”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-etymology-of-the-word-artifact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 06:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-etymology-of-the-word-artifact/</guid>
      <description>Sociologists use the term artifact to describe an item made by the skill of human. Interestingly they concern themselves with the production of the item and not its use; this is one of the largely infuriating problems with sociology. It is not in the production of an item that we are able to give things value but in their consumption and use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilitarianism Doesn’t Ask the Kinds of Questions I Care About</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 18:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/utilitarianism-doesnt-ask-the-kinds-of-questions-i-care-about/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I noted,
Since Socrates, we have been enamored with the question of the good life. What is the good life? How do we create the good life? What will the world look like when we implement the good life? Religion is an answer to this question, but at their core, each are questions about which.
Which values are good?
But these values are in constant flux. We have dialogues about them, and even so, it is hard to say that when we make decisions, we are basing these decisions on some sort of ethical/moral guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Industries and the Telecom Sector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>The classical definition of competitive price are those where price equal cost. The thought being, if a producer pushes their price above this line, they will not be able to capture customers, and if they lower their prices, they will not be able to cover their cost. We often think of cost as the money one spend to produce an item, but it includes more; there is there also the cost of managing the firm, and importantly it includes the minimum level of profit the firm must return to be attractive to investors and thus have capital inflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 00:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/comments/</guid>
      <description>Cyborgs are things of tension and intrigue. They are the work of fiction, living in between the social and technological, part human and machine. We too are cyborgs, living in the subtle shading of our narrative fictions, between the social and technological, part human and part machine.
I have begun to think more clearly about the famous bobo doll studies because it occurred to me the kinds of assumptions involved. Primarily this is a study on play/games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Legislation or, What is Customary Law?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-future-of-legislation-or-what-is-customary-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 22:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-future-of-legislation-or-what-is-customary-law/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading John Hasnas recently, which has been beneficial for a number of reasons, though it has been slightly toxic to my mental health. His telling of the history of law has made me rethink much of my conception of law. Mind you, I am not a lawyer, so I do not profess an intimate knowledge of legal scholarship, but his distinction between kinds of laws (customary law and judge made law) has pushed me down a number of interesting avenues of thought, and shored up something thinking, which I want to lay out here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Concern with Troy Davis Irks Me</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/why-the-concern-with-troy-davis-irks-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 18:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/why-the-concern-with-troy-davis-irks-me/</guid>
      <description>Let me start off saying this, it was horrible that Troy Davis got executed, beyond our country’s continued choice to execute criminals. I am sad that the burden of proof was so low that he was sent to his death.
Regardless, I think it was deplorable on the part of white America to care about Troy Davis. And for those who poured out grief, you, comrade, have no clue. Of course we had to care, he was a perfect victim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Quotes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/random-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/random-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Richard Rorty describing ironists and thus the entire hipster culture,
 [Ironists] realize that anything can be made to look good or bad by being redescribed … [They] are always aware that the terms in which they describe themselves are subject to change, always aware of the contingency and fragility of their final vocabularies and thus of their selves.
 The Prince’s important first sentences:
 Two aspects of animal life impressed me most during the journeys which I made in my youth in Eastern Siberia and Northern Manchuria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bureaucratic State – A Construction</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-bureaucratic-state-a-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 19:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-bureaucratic-state-a-construction/</guid>
      <description>I am going to begin using this page as a place to outline my theory of the Bureaucratic State
 In bureaucracies many people have the authority to say no, not the authority to say yes. It is in vogue to prognosticate on the ephemeral features of our society. The postmodern turn it is called. But a full application of this very simple viewpoint still lacks with regard to the bureaucratic state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Andy Grove Formula via Eric Schmidt</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-andy-grove-formula-via-eric-schmidt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 15:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-andy-grove-formula-via-eric-schmidt/</guid>
      <description>Eric Schmidt channeling Andy Grove:
 “This is easy to understand. High tech runs three-times faster than normal businesses. And the government runs three-times slower than normal businesses. So we have a nine-times gap.”
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erving Goffman on the Shore</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/erving-goffman-on-the-shore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 22:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/erving-goffman-on-the-shore/</guid>
      <description>How aware are the people on the Jersey Shore of their performance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Golden Era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/remember-the-golden-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 15:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/remember-the-golden-era/</guid>
      <description>When there are calls for regulation on the net, remember the good ol days,
 Most people have already forgotten how dark and unsignposted the Internet once was. A user in 1996, when the Web comprised hundreds of thousands of “sites” with millions of “pages,” did not expect to be able to search for “Olympics” and automatically find the official site of the Atlanta games. That was too hard a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentences to Commit to Memory</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/sentences-to-commit-to-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 04:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/sentences-to-commit-to-memory/</guid>
      <description>I am currently reading Franz Oppenheimer,
 The moment when the first conqueror spared his victim in order permanently to exploit him in productive work, was of incomparable historical significance. It gave birth to nation and state, to right and the higher economics, with all the developments and ramifications which have grown and which will hereafter grow out of them.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marshall McLuhan’s Extension</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/marshall-mcluhans-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/marshall-mcluhans-extension/</guid>
      <description>Some will argue that the changes we are experiencing are detrimental. I don’t take the same tact and others are beginning to agree,
 Andy Clark, a professor of philosophy at the University of Edinburgh in Scotland, says there’s a deeper principle to be found in the phantom limb assertion. In his book Natural Born Cyborgs, Clark claims that our brains depend entirely on perceived correlations in order to construct an arbitrary boundary between our bodies and the external world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley is Undervalued</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/silicon-valley-is-undervalued/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 19:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/silicon-valley-is-undervalued/</guid>
      <description>Marc Andreesen:
 Too much of the debate is still around financial valuation, as opposed to the underlying intrinsic value of the best of Silicon Valley’s new companies. My own theory is that we are in the middle of a dramatic and broad technological and economic shift in which software companies are poised to take over large swathes of the economy. More and more major businesses and industries are being run on software and delivered as online services—from movies to agriculture to national defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentences of Interest/Intrigue</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/sentences-of-interestintrigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 18:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/sentences-of-interestintrigue/</guid>
      <description>From Wired,
 “To the naked eye, two people may appear identical,” says Major Leandro Pavani Agostini, chief of military police in Sao Paolo. But these powerful shades can scan up to 400 faces per second, up to 50 yards away, using 46,000 biometric points to identify an individual and ensure a correct match.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Crack Attack: America’s Latest Drug Scare 1986-1992”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-crack-attack-americas-latest-drug-scare-1986-1992/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 02:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-crack-attack-americas-latest-drug-scare-1986-1992/</guid>
      <description>Rereading this article, I was astonished by a couple of sentences:
 America’s drug problems functioned as opportunities for the imposition of an old moral agenda and the appearance of a new social concern. Moreover, the remedies that followed from this view were in perfect harmony with “traditional family values” – individual moral discipline and abstinence, combined with police and prisons for those who indulged. Such remedies avoided all questions about the economic and political sources of and solutions to America’s social problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the RIAA will Fall</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/why-the-riaa-will-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 02:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/why-the-riaa-will-fall/</guid>
      <description>The record industry, in its heyday, was the largest entertainment industry, bigger than sports and film. As the saying goes, big tree fall hard. In Politico’s morning tech roundup,
 Cary Sherman won’t take over the reins of the Recording Industry Association of America until Sept. 1, but the newly minted chief executive officer and chairman of the powerful music lobby already has a clear idea of what policy areas he wants to tackle right out of the gate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentences from Law Legislation and Liberty</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/sentences-from-law-legislation-and-liberty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 18:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/sentences-from-law-legislation-and-liberty/</guid>
      <description>Hayek:
 Man is as much a rule-following animal as a purpose-seeking one. And he is successful not because he knows why he ought to observe the rules which he does observe, or is even capable of stating all these rules in words, but because his thinking and acting are governed by rules which have by a process of selection been evolved in a society in which he lives, and which are thus the product of the experience of generations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Quotes on ‘The Foucault Effect: Studies in Governmentality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 22:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks, I have been become fascinated with the the history of policing, an area of dire import for libertarians of all stripes. Originally, the word police was synonymous with policy as we know it today e.g. civil administration, but slowly it began to take a different tact around the time when the modern state and economy were coming into their own. According to the etymology dictionary, the first force so-named in England was the Marine Police, set up 1798 to protect merchandise at the Port of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Economists</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/for-economists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 19:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/for-economists/</guid>
      <description>Don’t let us forget that the causes of human actions are usually immeasurably more complex and varied than our subsequent explanations of them.
-Fyodor Dostoevsky __</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphors I Enjoy Shakespearean Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/metaphors-i-enjoy-shakespearean-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/metaphors-i-enjoy-shakespearean-edition/</guid>
      <description>Over the past three weeks, we’ve seen just about every act there is to this political theater and, staying true to the time of Shakespeare, it seems every character is played by a man. Odds are that if there were more women in these discussions, the crisis would have been resolved by now.
 Is the debt ceiling really an issue that needs to be negotiated? Or, is it part of a horrible game?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limited Government vs. Big Government and Policing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/limited-government-vs-big-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 15:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/limited-government-vs-big-government/</guid>
      <description>It is not as simple as limited government and big government. Will Wilkinson explains,
 In reality, Americans get a mix of all this from their government. We get some totally legit public goods. We get certain goods and services, generally at a reduced level of quality, that some people would have paid for anyway but others can’t afford. We get a lot of straight-up destruction of wealth and welfare from deadweight loss, negative-sum transfers, and stupid wars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wille Zum Leben</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/wille-zum-leben/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 21:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/wille-zum-leben/</guid>
      <description>I use Schopenhauer’s term in a looser manner. Nevertheless, it just rolls off the tongue,
 White-footed mice, stranded on isolated urban islands, are evolving to adapt to urban stress. Fish in the Hudson have evolved to cope with poisons in the water. Native ants find refuge in the median strips on Broadway. And more familiar urban organisms, like bedbugs, rats and bacteria, also mutate and change in response to the pressures of the metropolis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Choice Economics in Policing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/public-choice-economics-in-policing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 20:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/public-choice-economics-in-policing/</guid>
      <description>Public choice applies to policing,
 In the police world, there are good arrests and better arrests, but there is no such thing as a bad arrest. In recent years, measures of “productivity” have achieved an almost totemic significance. And because they are so easy to count, arrests have come to outweigh more important but harder-to-quantify variables such as crimes prevented, fights mitigated, or public fears assuaged.
There’s an argument that putting pressure on rank-and-file officers to make lots of arrests is a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-on-adam-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 20:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-on-adam-smith/</guid>
      <description>Two things.
A. Adam Smith used the invisible hand metaphor once in the Wealth of Nations. It was not a central concept but a central metaphor. Smith used a number of these metaphors to describe what he saw happening around him, but this is not to say that it is the same as a concept. We need to focus, not on the metaphor, but the meaning and the sense that he was trying to convey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Porter on Competition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/michael-porter-on-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 17:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/michael-porter-on-competition/</guid>
      <description>An oldie but a goodie:
 Competition for proﬁts goes beyond established industry rivals to include four other competitive forces as well: customers, suppliers, potential entrants, and substitute products. The extended rivalry that results from all ﬁve forces deﬁnes an industry’s structure and shapes the nature of competitive interaction within an industry.
 I would also add in another competitive force – the public, or non-market forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Difference between Culture and Society?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/what-is-the-difference-between-culture-and-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 17:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/what-is-the-difference-between-culture-and-society/</guid>
      <description>Culture tends to refer to the artifact.
S0ciety/social tends to refer to the behavior or action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Club</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/welcome-to-the-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 17:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/welcome-to-the-club/</guid>
      <description>Google’s in-house philosopher explains his conversion from technologist to humanist,
 In learning the limits of my technologist worldview, I didn’t just get a few handy ideas about how to build better AI systems. My studies opened up a new outlook on the world. I would unapologetically characterize it as a personal intellectual transformation: a renewed appreciation for the elements of life that are not scientifically understood or technologically engineered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grab for the Graph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</guid>
      <description>Connecting search with social would be a huge step to completing the social graph. Currently Facebook has the lead on this one, but if Google is able to sidestep the privacy issues, which have been thorny, they could capture the pie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Considering Buying Hulu</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/apple-considering-buying-hulu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 15:06:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/apple-considering-buying-hulu/</guid>
      <description>Apple Inc. (AAPL), with $76.2 billion in cash and securities on its books, is considering making a bid for the Hulu online video service, two people with knowledge of the auction said.
Apple, the world’s second-most-valuable company, is in early talks that may lead to an offer for Hulu, said the people, who weren’t authorized to speak publicly.
 To make it more visceral,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are Responsible for Your Community</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/you-are-responsible-for-your-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 03:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/you-are-responsible-for-your-community/</guid>
      <description>Anil Dash doesn’t mince words,
 How many times have you seen a website say “We’re not responsible for the content of our comments.”? I know that when you webmasters put that up on your sites, you’re trying to address your legal obligation. Well, let me tell you about your moral obligation: Hell yes, you are responsible. You absolutely are. When people are saying ruinously cruel things about each other, and you’re the person who made it possible, it’s 100% your fault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Primatologist Discussing Wall Street Bonuses and Some Other Things</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-primatologist-discussing-wall-street-bonuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 17:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-primatologist-discussing-wall-street-bonuses/</guid>
      <description>Frans de Waal,
 I think the sense of fairness in humans is very strongly developed and that’s why we react so strongly to all the bonuses received by Wall Street executives. We want to know why they deserve these benefits. The anger we have towards Wall Street is probably a very old primate reaction that relates to cooperation. If you are a cooperative animal you need to watch what you get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desmond Morris in the Introduction to Chimpanzee Politics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/desmond-morris-in-the-introduction-to-chimpanzee-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 16:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/desmond-morris-in-the-introduction-to-chimpanzee-politics/</guid>
      <description>Quotable,
 The message of this important book is, in the author’s words, ‘the roots of politics are older than humanity.’ It is a message that pleases me but I suspect it will upset many, including some of our leading political figures.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you shut down debate? Call it anarchy!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/how-do-you-shut-down-debate-call-it-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 15:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/how-do-you-shut-down-debate-call-it-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>In an old chemist’s attic, so dreary and so mean,
Oh smell the fearful odors of nitroglycerine
They’re busy building bombs, and filling cans with nails
And little starving kiddies set up this tearful wail:
Oh, it’s sister Ginny’s turn to throw the bomb
The last one it was thrown by brother John
Mother’s aim is bad and the coppers all know Dad
So it’s sister Ginny’s turn to throw the bomb</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picard on the Closure of The News of the World</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/picard-on-the-closure-of-the-news-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 18:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/picard-on-the-closure-of-the-news-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Prof. Picard comments,
 Perhaps it was embarrassment—but it was more likely the loss of revenue, the loss of almost $3 billion in market value for the parent company because of declining share prices, the hundreds of millions of pounds in damages that will have to be paid, and the fact that the paper’s meltdown was endangering Murdoch’s takeover of BskyB—that led him to kill the paper.
 I tend to agree with him on this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contra-Marxism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/contra-marxism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 03:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/contra-marxism/</guid>
      <description>There is no denying it. Marx is an intellectual force. With an influence on economic sociology, critical theory, political science and the political economy of communication, his is a voice that is always singing loudly. To me, though, it is a swan song that never seems to end that final crescendo. His economics, which came directly from Adam Smith, Malthus and many of the classical economists, fell intellectually with the marginalist revolution and then was buried with Hayek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Mover Advantage Only Lasts So Long</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/first-mover-advantage-only-lasts-so-long/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 05:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/first-mover-advantage-only-lasts-so-long/</guid>
      <description>Via Metafilter, a look inside Research in Motion:
 Let’s rewind a few years. Picture yourself sitting in an executive briefing at Research In Motion. You’d hear Mike Lazaridis unequivocally state time and time again that BlackBerry smartphones would never have MP3 players or cameras in them because it just does not make sense when the company’s primary customers were the government and enterprise. “BlackBerry smartphones will never have cameras because the No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The War Metaphor, or Only Some Really Get It</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-war-metaphor-or-some-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 17:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-war-metaphor-or-some-get-it/</guid>
      <description>One of the reason I decided to go to graduate school was to better understand arguments, language, and their relationship to policy. Jerry Brito gets it, where few do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master’s Thesis Mayham</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/masters-thesis-mayham/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 15:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/masters-thesis-mayham/</guid>
      <description>Articles of interest for my master’s thesis:
An essay by Yochai Benkler challenging the notion of innate human selfishness and the rational actor theory. Link
To understand the economic crisis, you don’t need an economist, you need a psychologist. It is a morality play. Link
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Temptation of Meaning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-quote-by-slavoj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 15:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-quote-by-slavoj/</guid>
      <description>Even though I am decidedly against his economic views, I find Slavoj Zizek, like other Marxist philosophers, endlessly interesting. He is a challenge. But here is a quote that I think is well worth your time regardless of your politics/philosophy:
 Why is resisting the temptation of meaning so difficult? It’s incredible how we philosophers, even when so-called ordinary people approach us, ultimately the question is always the meaning of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Points from Brink Lindsey’s The Age of Abundance</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/some-interesting-points-from-brink-lindseys-the-age-of-abundance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 22:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/some-interesting-points-from-brink-lindseys-the-age-of-abundance/</guid>
      <description>This will get updated as I read through the book
 Adolescence came into general use around the turn of the 20th century as the time between adulthood and childhood became protracted enough to require a name. Everything about [Elvis] – his country-boy simplicity, the stripped-down rawness of his sound, and the screaming swooning pandemonium that surrounded him – proclaimed the rude vitality of the primitive. He was Rousseau’s noble savage, updated with a swivel and a sneer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Constitutional Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-on-constitutional-interpretation-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 23:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-on-constitutional-interpretation-part-1/</guid>
      <description>What follows is by no means new, but I just wanted to try to apply critiques central to literary theory to a new set of circumstances to better illuminate them for myself.
One of the pillars of the Tea Party is the importance of the Constitution. As the argument goes, the Constitution says what it means. It does not need to be interpreted by a judiciary because if the Framers had wished to include this statement or that clause, they would have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markets in Eveything Google Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</guid>
      <description>Google is developing a data exchange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McCloskey Explains the Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/mccloskey-explains-the-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 14:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/mccloskey-explains-the-problem/</guid>
      <description>McCloskey critiquing Marxism, extreme leftism and general allocation economics:
 No version of accumulation can explain the modern world, or else the modern world would have been ancient, since accumulation was.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sane Sentences on the Prison System</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/sane-sentences-on-the-prison-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 14:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/sane-sentences-on-the-prison-system/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Knapp:
 Guilt versus innocence? What weight do they carry when placed opposite the prison construction lobby and the police and “corrections” unions, who stand ready to weigh in with money and endorsements for any politician whose line is “more arrests, more convictions, more jails” … or to come down like a ton of bricks on any candidate who suggests, however mildly, that more than two million prisoners and nearly one in every thirty Americans under “correctional supervision” may be overdoing it just a tad?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unity of Liberals</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-unity-of-liberals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 23:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-unity-of-liberals/</guid>
      <description>In order to alleviate a system marked with inequality, all liberals allocate guilt, albeit in different places. For Marxists, it is capital. For feminists, gender is to blame. For libertarians, it is the state, and for your run of the mill whole wheat liberal, it is big business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was the American Revolution Conservative?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/was-the-american-revolution-conservative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 22:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/was-the-american-revolution-conservative/</guid>
      <description>A simple question desires a simple answer.
The overturning of political relations of authority is the essence of a revolution. In the French case, a certain idealistic zeal led to more, a bloodletting and then an overturning of the social relations. Regardless, any revolution because it changes relations of authority and power are by their very definition not conservative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Interesting Points from an American Interest Article</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/some-interesting-points-from-an-american-interest-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 18:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/some-interesting-points-from-an-american-interest-article/</guid>
      <description>Some interesting points from this American Interest article:
 There is no ‘Iraqi People’. The phrase should be banned as misleading and purely rhetorical. . . . What is not understood is that Iraq, like the other countries of the region, still stands at a level of social evolution where the family, clan, tribe and sect command major allegiance. The idea of the individual autonomous voter, necessary and commonplace in our own systems, is relatively foreign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Profane</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 16:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/on-the-profanity-of-leftists/</guid>
      <description>One of the most fundamental distinctions in human thought is between the profane (profanum) and sacred (sacrum). Summarized by Nisbet,
The opposite of this is the profane, which is the utilitarian, individualistic world that we all inhabit. To see it another way, the profane revolves around the concerns of the individuals, while the sacred includes the concerns of the community. As Durkheim explained, people feel that the moral truths of the sacred are far more important than just personal preferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Lee on Patent Law</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/tim-lee-on-patent-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/tim-lee-on-patent-law/</guid>
      <description>Tim Lee charting the intersection of law and innovation:
 Getting software patents takes a lot of work, but it’s not primarily engineering effort. The complexity of software and low standards for patent eligibility mean that software engineers produce potentially patentable ideas all the time. But most engineers don’t think of these relatively trivial ideas as “inventions” worthy of a patent. What’s needed to get tens of thousands of patents is a re-education campaign to train engineers to write down every trivial idea that pops into their heads, and a large and disciplined legal bureaucracy to turn all those ideas into patent applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 18:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/innovation/</guid>
      <description>From Marginal Revolution:
 Take the case of the Netherlands. Unbeknown to most people, it is world’s third largest agricultural exporter, despite having little land (it has the world’s fifth highest population density). This has been possible because the Dutch have “industrialised” agriculture by, for example, deploying hydroponic agriculture (growing plants in water) that uses computer-controlled feeding of high-quality chemicals—something that would not have been possible if the Netherlands did not have some of the world’s most advanced chemical and electronics industries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of Google</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</guid>
      <description>Via Eli Dourado, this deserves to be quoted in full:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufactured Moral Outrage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/manufactured-moral-outrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/manufactured-moral-outrage/</guid>
      <description>The title explains it all, or those with the loudest voices and most raucous moral outrage are the ones that seem to hold the least informed opinions:
From the point of view of a media scholar, it is interesting to see how the facts got so distorted. This decision was a huge upset to many of the commentators, Nancy Grace is my particular favorite, and yet as the closing arguments brutally explain, there is no way a jury could legally convict her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition in the Markets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/competition-in-the-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 22:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/competition-in-the-markets/</guid>
      <description>Apple is going to price the iPhone 3GS at zero dollars when the iPhone 5 is released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words of Wisdom from Will Wilkinson</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/words-of-wisdom-from-will-wilkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 18:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/words-of-wisdom-from-will-wilkinson/</guid>
      <description>Will Wilkinson:
 The pretence that everything has to be “fair” or “make sense”, or that anything at all can be done about the present providential dispensation is the height of folly. But such is the human condition, especially the condition of New York City-based humans.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Werner Herzog on Colbert</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/werner-herzog-on-colbert/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 18:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/werner-herzog-on-colbert/</guid>
      <description>From the Colbert Report,
 If I were only fact based, the book of books in literature would be the Manhattan phone directory – 4 million entries everything correct, but it dusts out of my ears and I do not know, do they dream at night? Does Mr. Jonathan Smith cry in his pillow at night? We do not know anything when we check the correct entries in the phone directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Israel Kirzner on Advertising</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/israel-kirzner-on-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 13:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/israel-kirzner-on-advertising/</guid>
      <description>This link is self recommending.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Drug War and Privacy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-drug-war-and-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 20:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-drug-war-and-privacy/</guid>
      <description>A rundown of the most egregious privacy offenses made by the government in the name of morality:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Private Provision of Public Goods</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-private-provision-of-public-goods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 19:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-private-provision-of-public-goods/</guid>
      <description>The private provision of public goods, i.e. goods which are both non-excludeable and non-rival, is the prime concern of anarcho-capitalism. An example of this kind of philosophy can be found in Roderick Long’s writings, a pithy version of which was recently posted on his web site,
 Charlotte Ward asks us to imagine a world without taxes. (“Don’t like taxes? Imagine a world without these services,” Tuesday.)
Okay, let’s try. What would it be like?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blair Levin on CSPAN</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/blair-levin-on-cspan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2011 23:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/blair-levin-on-cspan/</guid>
      <description>I was watching an interview with Blair Levin today on CSPAN and as he was questioned about the AT&amp;amp;T merger, he mentioned a new report by Berstein Research, which I was not aware of. A ZDNet article fills in the gaps,
 Moffett noted that 44 million Americans are below the poverty line and 50 million are on food stamps. “Considerations of pricing power in telecom and media industries have traditionally been about competition, not affordability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Sentences</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/great-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 19:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/great-sentences/</guid>
      <description>Mises:
 Nations and languages are not unchangeable categories but, rather, provisional results of a process in constant flux; they change from day to day, and so we see before us a wealth of intermediate forms whose classification requires some pondering.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attorney Robert Corn-Revere Defends The Right to Offend</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/attorney-robert-corn-revere-defends-the-right-to-offend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 15:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/attorney-robert-corn-revere-defends-the-right-to-offend/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 18:07:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/perfect/</guid>
      <description>From Austro-Athenian Empire:
 “[Police officers] need to move quickly, in split seconds, without giving a lot of thought to what the adverse consequences for them might be. … [A]nything that’s going to have a chilling effect on an officer moving – an apprehension that he’s being videotaped and may be made to look bad – could cost him or some citizen their life.” — Jim Pasco, Fraternal Order of Police</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Babbage’s Difference Engine No. 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/babbages-difference-engine-no-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 21:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/babbages-difference-engine-no-2/</guid>
      <description>Reading “The Information” by Gleick made me look this up:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assorted Links</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/assorted-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 20:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/assorted-links/</guid>
      <description> “Major Metaphors of Communication and some Constructivist Reflections on their Use” by Klaus Krippendorff Early Krugman on our dangerous obsession with competition Related to Krugman, recent studies on our closest relatives finds that cooperation not competition is the key to our evolution Depression and the end of impersonal trust   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth, Water, Air and Fire</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/earth-water-air-and-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 18:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/earth-water-air-and-fire/</guid>
      <description>From Eureka The Birth of Science by Andrew Gregory:
 The philosopher Empedocles of Acragas introduced the four elements of earth, water, air and fire, which were to become standard in Greek thought. These should not be understood as literally earth, water, and so on, but in a slightly more abstract manner as solid, liquid, gas and fire or as principles of solidity, fluidity, gasesousness and fieriness. (pg. 28)
 Some things not new but worth reviewing and remembering:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frame Incommensurability</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/frame-incommensurability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 17:57:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/frame-incommensurability/</guid>
      <description>Framing theory is one of the bulwarks of communication scholarship. For social scientists, a frame is seen as the way that a person interprets and gives meaning to the world. They are filters that we use to make sense of events and make decisions. Think about yourself. You see the world through a lens that is not the same as others. You interpret events with a given set of schema and viewpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intense</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/intense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 21:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/intense/</guid>
      <description>From Marginal Revolution:
 Even if it is assumed that the daily number of calories available for work was the same in the United States in 1860 as today, the intensity of work per hour would have been well below today’s levels, since the average number of hours worked in 1860 was 1.75 times as great as today. During the mid nineteenth century, only slaves on southern gang-system plantations appear to have worked at levels of intensity per hour approaching current standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Sentences</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/interesting-sentences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 19:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/interesting-sentences/</guid>
      <description>From this blog comes this paragraph:
 So losing our belief in free will could have negative effects on those around us. It could also undermine our own success in life. In a recent study, Tyler Stillman of Florida State University, working with Vohs, Baumeister and others, found that people who said they believed strongly in free will also tended to have more positive expectations about their career success. Is this just delusional thinking?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forty Literary Terms You Should Know</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/forty-literary-terms-you-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 23:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/forty-literary-terms-you-should-know/</guid>
      <description>From the Centered Librarian, 40 literary terms you should know:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bulleted Review of James Gleick’s The Information</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-bulleted-review-of-james-gleicks-the-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 21:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-bulleted-review-of-james-gleicks-the-information/</guid>
      <description>Aristotelians used motion to describe a whole range of actions, from peaches ripening and a stone falling to a child growing and a body decaying. p. 7 “Economics is reorganizing itself as an information science” p. 9 The Gospel of Mark begins, “In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God.” As another web site notes, “The word for “word” here is “logos”, the Greek word for the indwelling logic, or rational order of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Claude Shannon is Cute</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/claude-shannon-is-cute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 20:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/claude-shannon-is-cute/</guid>
      <description>Claude Shannon in A Mathematical Theory of Communication:
 The fundamental problem of communication is that of reproduction at one point either exactly or approximately a message selected at another point. Frequently the messages have meaning; that is, they refer to or are correlated according to some system with certain physical or conceptual entities. These semantic aspects of communication are irrelevant to the engineering problem. The significant aspect is that the actual message is one selected from a set of possible messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics is Institutionalized Government</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/politics-is-institutionalized-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/politics-is-institutionalized-government/</guid>
      <description>At an e-government conference today, one of the speakers said
 Government’s biggest obstacle is politics.
 No. Politics is institutionalized through governments. Or, politics is institutionalized government. It is not exogenous to the process, it is constituent of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Metaphors of Common(ers)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-metaphors-of-commoners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-metaphors-of-commoners/</guid>
      <description>I have been following a bit of this Common controversy and it just hit me that white people do not understand rap music can be metaphorical. I was think of the opposite side of this. Even if Common was making “cop killing” and incendiary remarks against Bush, that does not mean that he was going to do it. It is an allegory. Just because you kill someone in a lyric or a play or a movie, that does not mean that you hate them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English by the Numbers</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/english-by-the-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 19:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/english-by-the-numbers/</guid>
      <description>An oldie but a goodie:
 The first surprise, says Pinker, is that books contain “a huge amount of lexical dark matter.” Even after excluding proper nouns, more than 50% of the words in the n-gram database do not appear in any published dictionary. Widely used words such as “deletable” and obscure ones like “slenthem” (a type of musical instrument) slipped below the radar of standard references. By the research team’s estimate, the size of the English language has nearly doubled over the past century, to more than 1 million words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtraction not Addition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/subtraction-not-addition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 19:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/subtraction-not-addition/</guid>
      <description>From Ben Atlas:
 People think knowledge is an addition rather than a subtraction. People think you heal yourself by an addition (drugs, workouts, amulets, superstitions) rather than subtraction of toxic foods, toxic ideas, toxic friends plus an addition of a good night sleep.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observances</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/observances/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 22:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/observances/</guid>
      <description>We do not desire money. We desire prestige/wealth. Money is just a sign. The Rawlsian original position is a game theoretical situation. As such, it doesn’t represent reality. Responsibility finds its first use in the late 1700s, at the beginning of modern “capitalism.” Before this, we were bound by duty. Duty and responsibility are not the same thing. The rise of capitalism meant the end of debtor prison. The contradiction between the virtues of the micocasm and the order of the macrocasm is the essence of tragedy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith On Language</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/adam-smith-on-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 20:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/adam-smith-on-language/</guid>
      <description>The Blessed Adam Smith:
 Nobody ever saw a dog make a fair and deliberate exchange of one bone for another with another dog. Nobody ever saw one animal by its gestures and natural cries signify to another, this is mine, that yours; I am willing to give this for that. When an animal wants to obtain something either of a man or of another animal, it has no other means of persuasion but to gain the favour of those whose service it requires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is a False Dichotomy, or, Why I Hate the Word Or</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/why-i-hate-the-word-or/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 17:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/why-i-hate-the-word-or/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan Alex Howard, but this kind of headline really irks me: “Are the Internet and Social Media ‘Tools of Freedom’ or ‘Tools of Oppression?” As the article goes on to say, “The short answer is that these technologies can be both.” I am sorry but that is both the short answer and the long answer.
Let’s be a little more intelligent about this discussion. The first paragraph colors the entire argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Research About the Net</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/some-research-about-the-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/some-research-about-the-net/</guid>
      <description>Who Says What to Whom on Twitter
 We study several longstanding questions in media communications research, in the context of the microblogging service Twitter, regarding the production, flow, and consumption of information. To do so, we exploit a recently introduced feature of Twitter—known as Twitter lists—to distinguish between elite users, by which we mean specifically celebrities, bloggers, and representatives of media outlets and other formal organizations, and ordinary users. Based on this classification, we find a striking concentration of attention on Twitter—roughly 50% of tweets consumed are generated by just 20K elite users—where the media produces the most information, but celebrities are the most followed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Canon of Media Studies</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-canon-of-media-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 04:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-canon-of-media-studies/</guid>
      <description>As I put this list together, this post will be populated.
Media Ecology Marshall McLuhan – The Gutenburg Galaxy
Marshall McLuhan – Understanding Media
Harold Innis – The Bis of Communication
Walter Ong – Orality and Literacy
Lewis Mumford – Myth of the Machine Vol 1 – Technics and Human Development
Lewis Mumford – Myth of the Machine Vol 2 – Pentagon of Power
Eric Havelock – Preference to Plato</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quote from Frank Lloyd Wright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-quote-from-frank-lloyd-wright/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 20:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-quote-from-frank-lloyd-wright/</guid>
      <description>A free America… means just this: individual freedom for all, rich or poor, or else this system of government we call democracy is only an expedient to enslave man to the machine and make him like it.
 Let’s not forget that he also designed this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercantilism is Dead, Long Live Mercantilism!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/mercantilism-is-dead-long-live-mercantilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 22:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/mercantilism-is-dead-long-live-mercantilism/</guid>
      <description>Here is the hook for this Econlib feature article
 Many Americans may not realize that some of today’s political leaders and mainstream media espouse ideas that were discredited and left for dead over two hundred years ago. As in any number of horror flicks, sometimes the dead don’t stay that way.
 You cannot deny the power of power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Newspapers in the 18th Century</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/regulation-of-newspapers-in-the-18th-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 19:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/regulation-of-newspapers-in-the-18th-century/</guid>
      <description>Paul Starr again:
 Throughout the century, the absence of regulatory obstacles to newspapers contributed to their growth. No guild regulations limited entry into printing and the Stamp Act of 1712 did not apply to the colonies.
 and
 Throughout most of the colonial era, however, there was no system of partisan politics to support partisan journalism. And with only a limited local demand for their services, printers typically maximized their potential clients and advertisers by not taking sides in local controversies… Printers avoided offending the powerful by keeping divisive issues entirely out of their newspapers, stifling debate rather than promoting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April is the Cruellest Month</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/april-is-the-cruellest-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 04:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/april-is-the-cruellest-month/</guid>
      <description>April is the cruellest month, breeding
Lilacs out of the dead land, mixing
Memory and desire, stirring
Dull roots with spring rain.
Winter kept us warm, covering
Earth in forgetful snow, feeding
A little life with dried tubers.
 &amp;lt;td align=&amp;quot;right&amp;quot; valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a name=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Lilacs out of the dead land, mixing &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td align=&amp;quot;right&amp;quot; valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a name=&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Memory and desire, stirring &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td align=&amp;quot;right&amp;quot; valign=&amp;quot;top&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a name=&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt; Dull roots with spring rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aphorism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/aphorism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 04:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/aphorism/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the economy is production not employment.
 Also, Art is long, life is short, opportunity fleeting, experiment dangerous, judgment difficult.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Century of the Broken Contract</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-century-of-the-broken-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 04:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-century-of-the-broken-contract/</guid>
      <description>HT to Deirdre McCloskey regarding the last point:
In reading Ostrom on game theory, a curious thing popped up. Communication negates a decent amount of experimental work. Communication allows for ethics, reciprocity and especially shame to buttress the bargaining situation, changing it indelibly. Once you allow prisoners to talk, they are going to find the best outcome. Some other problems also arise when considering game theory.
First, there is the obvious issue of bargaining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing Too Much, Not Even Righteousness</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/nothing-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 03:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/nothing-too-much/</guid>
      <description>From FL Lucas’ book aptly titled Tragedy
 There, face to face, stand arrayed the opposite ideals – Apollo and Dionysus, the god of Dorian discipline and the god of the license of the wild. Yet both are Greek both lay claim to wisdom: and instead of burning the votaries of Dionysus at the stake, when we came storming on a wave of enthusiasm from the fastnesses of Thrace, the priests of Apollo gave his untamed younger brother, the son likewise of Zeus, a share in Apollo’s temple beneath the twin crags of Delphi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert McChesney is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 23:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Talking about the 1400 and 1500s:
That is from Paul Starr’s book The Creation of the Media, stating the obvious: newspaper production has always been about profits. Contrary to Robert McChesney, they aren’t special in any economic sense and we should not treat them as anything other than businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Policy as a Space</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/tech-policy-as-a-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 18:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/tech-policy-as-a-space/</guid>
      <description>A recent podcast with Alex Howard, Tim Karr and Christopher Preble at the Cato Institute has got me thinking about the way technology is conceptualized in tech policy circles. First off and I mean no offense to the parties involved, but there is a dearth of knowledge about media history. I am not saying that these policy analysts do not know contemporary telecom policy; in fact, I am in awe of their knowledge of the 1920s onward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos/Order</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/chaosorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 05:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/chaosorder/</guid>
      <description>The remnants from the Enlightenment project sill impose a constraint on our thinking. Two of the core tenants that we have inherited are that
 there is an order/harmony, and it precedes our existence in it  This continues to be one of the defining features of Western thought. Campbell, in his glorious contribution to this side of criticism, made note of the difference between the East and the West in this regard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Small Problem With Economics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/one-small-problem-with-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 05:11:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/one-small-problem-with-economics/</guid>
      <description>Early last week, as I was preparing for a course in international political economy (IPE), I read an introductory article on the subject by Robert Gilpin. Aimed at the novice, it described the discipline by explaining how it is organized. To the political economist, information, interests and institutions are of central concern. And yet, just a few sentences previous, it was noted that the scientific method is the approach to IPE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 05:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/rationality/</guid>
      <description>Rationality is only an instrument. It is a tool to achieving goals. Where do these goals come from? That is the better question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phrases Worth Remembering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 04:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</guid>
      <description> Ideology is rhetorical. Privacy is not an value. It is a means to protecting other values. Academic thought is revolutionary, policy is marginalist. Germany was unified in 1871.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information, Episteme and Techne Part 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading about information and stumbled upon an OED entry on the subject. As Michael Proffitt, managing editor, OED said, “Compounds arising in that period [the 1800s] reflect information as a commodity with supply and demand: information-giving (dating from 1829), information-seeking (1869), information gathering (1893).”
Proffitt is mistaken about about the commodity metaphor, and it is a similar one made in Marxist and Marxian thought. Once you make a concept a commodity, you have stripped it of value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demand for Profits</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-demand-for-profits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 16:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-demand-for-profits/</guid>
      <description>At least since the 1400s, it has been there:
 One fact must not be lost sight of: the printer and the bookseller worked above all and from the beginning for profit
 From “The Coming of the Book: The Impact of Printing 1450-1800“</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragedy and Freewill in a Previous Era</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 02:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/tragedy-and-freewill-in-a-previous-era/</guid>
      <description>For the pre-Socratic authors, tragedy was a very simple thing. Homer, being the bridge between the archaic and the ancient, exemplified this tragedy. Tragedy for this group was mankind going against fate. Tragedy was man’s betting of his own ability (hubris) against what the gods knew to be the future. This is why tragedy has been such a powerful story over the ages, I would argue. It taps into this very old, perhaps even subconscious belief that things in the world are ordered and thus determined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verizon is Making A Mistake</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/verizon-is-making-a-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 02:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/verizon-is-making-a-mistake/</guid>
      <description>According to Minyanville, Verizon might be giving us a glimpse of the future for its relationship with Google.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative AD-dition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/creative-ad-dition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 02:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/creative-ad-dition/</guid>
      <description>The next couple of years are going to be very interesting for the advertising industry. Even in the sector that I work in, digital marketing, is undergoing constant and massive change. Thats why I am interested in this
 We shall see where it takes us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craigslist is a Mess</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/craigslist-is-a-mess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 19:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/craigslist-is-a-mess/</guid>
      <description>Classifieds site Craigslist has been linked with 330 crimes, 12 murders and 105 robberies or assaults in the United States last year due to anonymous interactions on the site, says a new study.
 Even if this weren’t a story paid for by a competitor, which Mike Masnick explains is indeed the case, Craiglist, as a community is still a better place than most. That’s a little bit of an understatement, actually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh That Looks Shiny!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/oh-that-looks-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 21:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/oh-that-looks-shiny/</guid>
      <description>There is no end to my respect of Apple. They are flawless marketers and companies the world over should take note, if they haven’t already. A recent article in BusinessWeek illustrates this nicely. This quote is long and bulky but worth it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in the Un-Sane Asylum: David Brooks Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/living-in-the-un-sane-asylum-david-brooks-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 04:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/living-in-the-un-sane-asylum-david-brooks-edition/</guid>
      <description>The older I get, which isn’t really a high number at this point, the more I think I’m living in an insane asylum. So, in a new series called Living in the Un-Sane Asylum (U.S.A.) I am going to be bring attention to those people who seem to have a grip on some sort of sanity in this world. Here is the first of the posts:
I do appreciate Brooks for bringing up this point, but personally his column leaves me wanting more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Press is protesting Google</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/free-press-is-protesting-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/free-press-is-protesting-google/</guid>
      <description>Yes, it is true. Free Press is protesting Google today at Mountain View.
Personally, I think Google’s stance on net neutrality was foolish to begin with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now I’m confident we won’t have another economic downturn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/now-im-confident-we-wont-have-another-economic-downturn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/now-im-confident-we-wont-have-another-economic-downturn/</guid>
      <description>Dunstan Prial of Fox Business Network writes that the Securities and Exchange Commission is now exempt from public requests for information, including Freedom of Information Requests, as part of the financial regulation overhaul.
 Here is the link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I consider Starbucks to be quite common, but that’s just me</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/i-consider-starbucks-to-be-quite-common-but-thats-just-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/i-consider-starbucks-to-be-quite-common-but-thats-just-me/</guid>
      <description>Great quote from Jason Kuznicki talking about the recent ban of sugared soft drinks in vending machines in San Francisco:
Quite frankly, I think Starbucks is pedestrian. Intelligentsia is the way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Course Free Press Authored It</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</guid>
      <description>From the, “Yes, of course we all knew this” file,
I think its great that an organization helping to solve the Internet’s problems cannot even delete the metadata. Really?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Foolishness of Jonathan Chait</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</guid>
      <description>Talking about financial reform, Jonathan Chait over at TNR lamented the lack of knowledge within liberal circles on how to move forward. As he says,
The belief that any regulation could prevent the next crisis is foolish. Like clockwork, there has been an economic downturn every ten years for the last 400 years, at least. Even though he is not willing to come right out and say it, Chait does seem to admit the futility of tough regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and iAd</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</guid>
      <description>I really don’t know how this went past me, but I was watching Fast Money today and Kaminsky made note of Apple going into direct search. To make this a little more solid, look at this,
The always insightful Picard makes this more tangible:
Only time will allow us to understand how this is going to work out, but regardless, it is an interesting time to be in media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of the reasons why newspapers are going out of business</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/one-of-the-reasons-why-newspapers-are-going-out-of-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/one-of-the-reasons-why-newspapers-are-going-out-of-business/</guid>
      <description>From the New York Times,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasmussen, the FCC and Rape Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Adam Thierer over at Technology Liberation Front posted a Rasmussen poll that suggests,
He believes that it is due to FCC’s overreaching actions:
It is actually a little simpler than that. I don’t think many people know or even care about the FCC and Internet regulation. The story that broke this past week, which is probably the cause of this drop, more broadly fits into the concept of intrusion, which has been all the rage these past couple months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tony Judt is wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/tony-judt-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>I just read a new essay from Tony Judt he wrote in the New York Times Book Review. For me, the takeaway part was the very beginning where he said,
Later, he laments, saying,
With the worst of the economic crisis behind us, social commentators like Judt are calling for action, demanding that leaders and society change to advert another economic crisis. Sadly, this is yet another lofty aspiration based on fallacious Enlightenment ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koch Summer Fellowship Essay: Democratizing Technology</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2009/koch-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 18:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2009/koch-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>So here is my Koch Fellowship application:
In the 1930s, two visions for the decline of Western civilization were predicted. Broadly speaking, these were the Huxleyan outcome and the Orwellian outcome. For the past three decades, cultural theorists such as Neil Postman and Jean Baudrillard have warned us about a Huxleyan future, one in which society, shaped by wave after wave of technological advancements, turns itself into a giant burlesque show, a hedonistic landscape of lost meanings and distant relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
