<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History of Technology on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/history-of-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History of Technology on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/history-of-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why It’s Important That The Internet Created Technopopulism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</guid>
      <description>After finishing ITIF’s new report on technopopulism, I couldn’t help but think, isn’t this missing a couple of pages, about, you know, the Internet?
While there is much to like about the report, the missing piece, the missing message, as McLuhan famously quipped, is the medium.
Here is the basic gist of the report. In the old days, tech policy was decided by educated wonks who knew the finer points of policy and could make reasoned arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Paradoxes Of Nostalgia</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/paradoxes-nostalgia/</guid>
      <description>Svetlana Boym has a fascinating article on nostalgia. Here are some choice parts:
Interesting essay throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With Technology, the Past is No Longer a Foreign Country</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/technology-past-longer-foreign-country/</guid>
      <description>Novelist L. P. Hartley once wrote, “The past is a foreign country: they do things differently there.” Ironically, we may no longer live in his world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommunication’s Regulatory Cat and Mouse Game</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Jon Henke has reviewed “The People’s Network: The Political Economy of the Telephone in the Gilded Age” for Reason. I haven’t read the book, but his take has placed it on the top of the list. As anyone who has read about the history of telecommunication regulation, policy formation is and has been a cat-and-mouse game between regulators and the regulated. Jon explains:
What can this history tell us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Daniel Boorstin’s “The Republic of Technology”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>“An athlete of steel and iron with not a superfluous ounce of metal on it” exclaimed William Dean Howells when he recalled the gigantic 700-ton Corliss steam engine that towered over Machinery Hall at the Philadelphia International Exhibition. A festive crowd cheered as the engine set in motion a wonderful assortment of machines—pumping water, combing wool, spinning cotton, tearing hemp, printing newspapers, lithographing wallpaper, sewing cloth, folding envelopes, sawing logs, shaping wood, making shoes—8,000 machines spread over 13 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Thomas P. Hughes “American Genesis”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 21:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</guid>
      <description>When more histories of technology that take the critical stance of the best histories of politics are written, American will realize that not only their remarkable achievements but many of their deep and persistent problems arise, in the name of order, system, and control, from the mechanization and systematization of life and from the sacrifice of the organic and the spontaneous p 4 As historian and social critic Lewis Mumford so eloquently insisted decades ago, technology is both shaper of, and is shaped by, values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert McChesney is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 23:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Talking about the 1400 and 1500s:
That is from Paul Starr’s book The Creation of the Media, stating the obvious: newspaper production has always been about profits. Contrary to Robert McChesney, they aren’t special in any economic sense and we should not treat them as anything other than businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
