<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regulation on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/regulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regulation on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What’s The FCC’s Rush on New Net Neutrality Rules?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>Network neutrality rules have failed to pass Congress and the courts countless times, so what’s the FCC’s rush now? Scott Cleland explores in an op-ed at the Daily Caller:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Policy Becomes a Battleground for Lifestyles</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 20:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/policy-becomes-battleground-life-styles/</guid>
      <description>The WSJ quotes a section of Richard Wagner ’s “Economic Policy in a Liberal Democracy” (1996):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Industries and the Telecom Sector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>The classical definition of competitive price are those where price equal cost. The thought being, if a producer pushes their price above this line, they will not be able to capture customers, and if they lower their prices, they will not be able to cover their cost. We often think of cost as the money one spend to produce an item, but it includes more; there is there also the cost of managing the firm, and importantly it includes the minimum level of profit the firm must return to be attractive to investors and thus have capital inflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phrases Worth Remembering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 04:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/phrases-worth-remembering/</guid>
      <description> Ideology is rhetorical. Privacy is not an value. It is a means to protecting other values. Academic thought is revolutionary, policy is marginalist. Germany was unified in 1871.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I consider Starbucks to be quite common, but that’s just me</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/i-consider-starbucks-to-be-quite-common-but-thats-just-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/i-consider-starbucks-to-be-quite-common-but-thats-just-me/</guid>
      <description>Great quote from Jason Kuznicki talking about the recent ban of sugared soft drinks in vending machines in San Francisco:
Quite frankly, I think Starbucks is pedestrian. Intelligentsia is the way to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Course Free Press Authored It</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/of-course-free-press-authored-it/</guid>
      <description>From the, “Yes, of course we all knew this” file,
I think its great that an organization helping to solve the Internet’s problems cannot even delete the metadata. Really?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Foolishness of Jonathan Chait</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/the-foolishness-of-jonathan-chait/</guid>
      <description>Talking about financial reform, Jonathan Chait over at TNR lamented the lack of knowledge within liberal circles on how to move forward. As he says,
The belief that any regulation could prevent the next crisis is foolish. Like clockwork, there has been an economic downturn every ten years for the last 400 years, at least. Even though he is not willing to come right out and say it, Chait does seem to admit the futility of tough regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasmussen, the FCC and Rape Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/rasmussen-the-fcc-and-rape-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Adam Thierer over at Technology Liberation Front posted a Rasmussen poll that suggests,
He believes that it is due to FCC’s overreaching actions:
It is actually a little simpler than that. I don’t think many people know or even care about the FCC and Internet regulation. The story that broke this past week, which is probably the cause of this drop, more broadly fits into the concept of intrusion, which has been all the rage these past couple months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
