<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Theory on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/information-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information Theory on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/information-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into the Regulation Market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</guid>
      <description>In response to the new Tyler Cowen and Alex Alex Tabarrok piece on information asymmetry, Arnold Kling wonders if:
My response:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why It’s Important That The Internet Created Technopopulism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</guid>
      <description>After finishing ITIF’s new report on technopopulism, I couldn’t help but think, isn’t this missing a couple of pages, about, you know, the Internet?
While there is much to like about the report, the missing piece, the missing message, as McLuhan famously quipped, is the medium.
Here is the basic gist of the report. In the old days, tech policy was decided by educated wonks who knew the finer points of policy and could make reasoned arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Genesis of the Career Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 16:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>I have begun in earnest to read through Annalee Saxenian’s “Regional Advantage,” charting the computer industry’s genesis in both Silicon Valley and along Boston’s Route 128. As she explains, the culture of work and the resulting firm structures in Silicon Valley differed significantly from those in Boston, giving it critical advantages to become the preeminent region of technology development.
Even in the early days of the 1950s and 1960s, the West Coast had a far more open and decentralized network of employees, which contributed to intense knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value As a Result of Pricing Mobile Data Use</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 19:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/value-result-pricing-mobile-data-use/</guid>
      <description>I was reading over the comments my former colleagues at the International Center for Law and Economics and TechFreedom filed on Title II reclassification to find these two paragraphs of pure Alchian bliss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information wants to be expensive as well as free</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/information-wants-expensive-well/</guid>
      <description>Famously, Stewart Brand noted that “information wants to be free.” But, that statement leaves off the other half of the phrase, thus burying the complexity of his thinking. In an email, he explained,
He continues in his book, “The MIT Media Lab”:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Eli Pariser’s “The Filter Bubble: What the Internet Is Hiding from You”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 20:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“To my preteen self, it seemed clear that the Internet was going to democratize the world, connecting us with better information and the power to act on it. The California futurists and techno-optimists in those pages spoke with a clear-eyed certainty; an inevitable, irresistible revolution was just around the corner, one that would flatten society, unseat the elites, and usher in a kind of freewheeling global utopia.” pg 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Filter Bubble introduces three dynamics we’ve never dealt with before: first, you are alone in it, as it is you own personal bubble. Second, it is invisible in its actions. Finally, you don’t choose to enter into the bubble. pp 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the cost of communication over large distances and to large groups of people has plummeted, we’re increasingly unable to attend to it all,” leading to what blogger and media analyst Steve Rubel calls the attention crash. p 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of personalization is appealing as a “return to a Ptolemaic universe in which the sun and everything else revolves around us.” p 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the filter bubble, there’s less room for the chance encounters that bring insight and learning” p 15 My reaction: &lt;em&gt;What does Kirzner have to say about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be the author of your life, professor Yochai Benkler argues, you have to be aware of a diverse array of options and lifestyles. When you enter a filter bubble, you’re letting companies that construct it choose which options you’re aware of. You may think that you’re the captain of your own destiny, but personalization can lead you down a road to a kind of informational determinism in which what you’ve clicked on in the past determines what you see next—a Web history you’re doomed to repeat.” p 16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Putnam defined two kinds of social capital: in-group oriented bonding capital represents those events when you meet an old friend, while bridging capital occurs when lots of people from different backgrounds come together to meet each other, like in a townhall. p 17&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information, Episteme and Techne Part 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/information-episteme-and-techne-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading about information and stumbled upon an OED entry on the subject. As Michael Proffitt, managing editor, OED said, “Compounds arising in that period [the 1800s] reflect information as a commodity with supply and demand: information-giving (dating from 1829), information-seeking (1869), information gathering (1893).”
Proffitt is mistaken about about the commodity metaphor, and it is a similar one made in Marxist and Marxian thought. Once you make a concept a commodity, you have stripped it of value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
