<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why It’s Important That The Internet Created Technopopulism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/the-internet-created-technopopulism/</guid>
      <description>After finishing ITIF’s new report on technopopulism, I couldn’t help but think, isn’t this missing a couple of pages, about, you know, the Internet?
While there is much to like about the report, the missing piece, the missing message, as McLuhan famously quipped, is the medium.
Here is the basic gist of the report. In the old days, tech policy was decided by educated wonks who knew the finer points of policy and could make reasoned arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Economic Environment Will TV Unbundling Create?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 22:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/change-financing-unbundling/</guid>
      <description>The Technology Policy Institute just went live with a video of their OTT event, exploring TV unbundling. There is a lot of solid material, but Laura Martin, a Senior Analyst at Needham &amp;amp; Company, explained what would happen if we went to an unbundled world:
 As soon as you unbundle, you lose advertising revenue. Immediately, you have to double the cost because of lost ad dollars. 1/2 of the revenues come from ads and the other 1/2 comes from subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markets in Eveything Google Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</guid>
      <description>Google is developing a data exchange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert McChesney is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 23:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/robert-mcchesney-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Talking about the 1400 and 1500s:
That is from Paul Starr’s book The Creation of the Media, stating the obvious: newspaper production has always been about profits. Contrary to Robert McChesney, they aren’t special in any economic sense and we should not treat them as anything other than businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and iAd</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</guid>
      <description>I really don’t know how this went past me, but I was watching Fast Money today and Kaminsky made note of Apple going into direct search. To make this a little more solid, look at this,
The always insightful Picard makes this more tangible:
Only time will allow us to understand how this is going to work out, but regardless, it is an interesting time to be in media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of the reasons why newspapers are going out of business</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/one-of-the-reasons-why-newspapers-are-going-out-of-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/one-of-the-reasons-why-newspapers-are-going-out-of-business/</guid>
      <description>From the New York Times,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
