<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moral Panics on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/moral-panics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moral Panics on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:24:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/moral-panics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Kids Are Going To Be Alright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 19:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-kids-are-going-to-be-alright/</guid>
      <description>Catchy headlines like “Heavy Social Media Use Linked With Mental Health Issues In Teens” and “Have Smartphones Destroyed a Generation?” advance a common trope of generational decline. But a new paper in Nature uses a new and rigorous analytical method to understand the relationship between adolescent well-being and digital technology, finding a “negative but small [link], explaining at most 0.4% of the variation in well-being.”
What really sets apart the new paper from Amy Orben and Andy Przybylski is that it aims to capture a more complete picture of how variables interact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Short Responses To The Pacing Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</guid>
      <description>Contemporary tech criticism displays an anti-nostalgia. Instead of being reverent for the past, anxiety about the future abounds. In these visions, the future is imagined as a strange, foreign land, beset with problems. And yet, to quote that old adage, tomorrow is the visitor that is always coming but never arrives. The future never arrives because we are assembling it today.
The distance between the now and the future finds its hook in tech policy in the pacing problem, a term describing the mismatch between advancing technologies and society’s efforts to cope with them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
