<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Media on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Media on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:48:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Demand Led Growth in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/demand-led-growth-in-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/demand-led-growth-in-social-media/</guid>
      <description>One part of this intriguing interview with the creator of the Medieval Reactions Twitter account really caught my eye:
Demand led content growth is a scary new world for content creators, one that really makes the old guard feel uneasy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Eli Pariser’s “The Filter Bubble: What the Internet Is Hiding from You”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 20:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“To my preteen self, it seemed clear that the Internet was going to democratize the world, connecting us with better information and the power to act on it. The California futurists and techno-optimists in those pages spoke with a clear-eyed certainty; an inevitable, irresistible revolution was just around the corner, one that would flatten society, unseat the elites, and usher in a kind of freewheeling global utopia.” pg 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Filter Bubble introduces three dynamics we’ve never dealt with before: first, you are alone in it, as it is you own personal bubble. Second, it is invisible in its actions. Finally, you don’t choose to enter into the bubble. pp 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the cost of communication over large distances and to large groups of people has plummeted, we’re increasingly unable to attend to it all,” leading to what blogger and media analyst Steve Rubel calls the attention crash. p 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of personalization is appealing as a “return to a Ptolemaic universe in which the sun and everything else revolves around us.” p 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the filter bubble, there’s less room for the chance encounters that bring insight and learning” p 15 My reaction: &lt;em&gt;What does Kirzner have to say about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be the author of your life, professor Yochai Benkler argues, you have to be aware of a diverse array of options and lifestyles. When you enter a filter bubble, you’re letting companies that construct it choose which options you’re aware of. You may think that you’re the captain of your own destiny, but personalization can lead you down a road to a kind of informational determinism in which what you’ve clicked on in the past determines what you see next—a Web history you’re doomed to repeat.” p 16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Putnam defined two kinds of social capital: in-group oriented bonding capital represents those events when you meet an old friend, while bridging capital occurs when lots of people from different backgrounds come together to meet each other, like in a townhall. p 17&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Networks and the Proliferating Performances of Identity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/social-networks-and-the-proliferating-performances-of-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 02:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/social-networks-and-the-proliferating-performances-of-identity/</guid>
      <description>Tom Chatfield’s essay on technology and language groks Walter Ong and under-appreciated Medium theory. He begins at the genesis of the written word and makes a huge arc to today’s moral themes. First the problem of information scarcity:
Yet the world is now one of information abundance and mediums of exchange:
Leading to, among other things, new expressions of identity on the Internet:
Chatfield is right. The biggest gulf between digital natives and digital immigrants lies in the negotiation of an authentic social performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Undermines Prevailing Theory that Technology is Isolating</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 15:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/research-undermines-prevailing-theory-that-technology-is-isolating/</guid>
      <description>An ever-present theme in the commentary of modern technology is its isolating effect. Yet the truth is far more complex. This Boston Review article on technology points to a paper supported by the Annenberg School of Communication that seems to suggest we are becoming more social. By conducting a content analysis of films from four public spaces over a thirty-year period, the behavior and characteristics of 143,593 people were coded. A couple of key findings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Daniel Boorstin’s “The Republic of Technology”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>“An athlete of steel and iron with not a superfluous ounce of metal on it” exclaimed William Dean Howells when he recalled the gigantic 700-ton Corliss steam engine that towered over Machinery Hall at the Philadelphia International Exhibition. A festive crowd cheered as the engine set in motion a wonderful assortment of machines—pumping water, combing wool, spinning cotton, tearing hemp, printing newspapers, lithographing wallpaper, sewing cloth, folding envelopes, sawing logs, shaping wood, making shoes—8,000 machines spread over 13 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
