<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Industries on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/network-industries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Industries on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/network-industries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking into the Regulation Market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/breaking-into-the-regulation-market/</guid>
      <description>In response to the new Tyler Cowen and Alex Alex Tabarrok piece on information asymmetry, Arnold Kling wonders if:
My response:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Genesis of the Career Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 16:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/genesis-career-entrepreneur/</guid>
      <description>I have begun in earnest to read through Annalee Saxenian’s “Regional Advantage,” charting the computer industry’s genesis in both Silicon Valley and along Boston’s Route 128. As she explains, the culture of work and the resulting firm structures in Silicon Valley differed significantly from those in Boston, giving it critical advantages to become the preeminent region of technology development.
Even in the early days of the 1950s and 1960s, the West Coast had a far more open and decentralized network of employees, which contributed to intense knowledge sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telecommunication’s Regulatory Cat and Mouse Game</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 17:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/telecommunications-regulatory-cat-mouse-game/</guid>
      <description>My former colleague Jon Henke has reviewed “The People’s Network: The Political Economy of the Telephone in the Gilded Age” for Reason. I haven’t read the book, but his take has placed it on the top of the list. As anyone who has read about the history of telecommunication regulation, policy formation is and has been a cat-and-mouse game between regulators and the regulated. Jon explains:
What can this history tell us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demand Destruction Signals Long Term Shift in Energy Markets</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/demand-destruction-signals-long-term-shift-in-energy-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 13:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/demand-destruction-signals-long-term-shift-in-energy-markets/</guid>
      <description>Recent estimates suggest the US might meet the Kyoto Protocol because of natural gas substitution. Slate is reporting on a related trend, energy demand destruction:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Industry Innovates With Contracts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/solar-industry-innovates-with-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 17:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/solar-industry-innovates-with-contracts/</guid>
      <description>Innovative products are not necessarily followed by broad adoption. There needs be a business model behind it.
Lynee Kiesling over at Knowledge Problem has a post on the solar industry, which is interesting throughout. She cites a New York Times article which helps to explain part of the mystery of innovation:
And there you go. Deregulate the whole thicket of laws surrounding electricity, put residential customers on a payment plan and solar becomes a much more attractive investment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Great Paragraph from Henry Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/a-great-paragraph-from-henry-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>From this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Daniel Boorstin’s “The Republic of Technology”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>“An athlete of steel and iron with not a superfluous ounce of metal on it” exclaimed William Dean Howells when he recalled the gigantic 700-ton Corliss steam engine that towered over Machinery Hall at the Philadelphia International Exhibition. A festive crowd cheered as the engine set in motion a wonderful assortment of machines—pumping water, combing wool, spinning cotton, tearing hemp, printing newspapers, lithographing wallpaper, sewing cloth, folding envelopes, sawing logs, shaping wood, making shoes—8,000 machines spread over 13 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Believe Everything you Hear</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 17:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/dont-believe-everything-you-hear/</guid>
      <description>It seems intuitive that the rise of the Internet and social networking sites has made us all more lonely. Because we are all constrained with our time and because online connections seem shallow, it logically follows that the more time we spend online in lieu of face-to-face interactions, the more lonely we are. Though, the empirical evidence is not as clear on this as we have been lead to believe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Industries and the Telecom Sector</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:29:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/competitive-industries-and-the-telecom-sector/</guid>
      <description>The classical definition of competitive price are those where price equal cost. The thought being, if a producer pushes their price above this line, they will not be able to capture customers, and if they lower their prices, they will not be able to cover their cost. We often think of cost as the money one spend to produce an item, but it includes more; there is there also the cost of managing the firm, and importantly it includes the minimum level of profit the firm must return to be attractive to investors and thus have capital inflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grab for the Graph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</guid>
      <description>Connecting search with social would be a huge step to completing the social graph. Currently Facebook has the lead on this one, but if Google is able to sidestep the privacy issues, which have been thorny, they could capture the pie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markets in Eveything Google Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</guid>
      <description>Google is developing a data exchange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory of Google</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/a-theory-of-google/</guid>
      <description>Via Eli Dourado, this deserves to be quoted in full:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
