<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Law on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/law/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Law on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:49:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Legal Advisories on the New Net Neutrality Rules</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 13:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/a-collection-of-legal-advisories-on-the-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>The new network neutrality rules have been out for almost a month now. Here is a short collection of legal opinions:
 “Net Neutrality V.3: What We Know So Far” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “A First Look Inside the Net Neutrality Order” by Paul J. Feldman at Fletcher, Heald &amp;amp; Hildreth’s CommLawBlog “The FCC’s Open Internet Order: New Net Neutrality Rules and Title II Regulation of Broadband” by Bennett L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s The FCC’s Rush on New Net Neutrality Rules?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>Network neutrality rules have failed to pass Congress and the courts countless times, so what’s the FCC’s rush now? Scott Cleland explores in an op-ed at the Daily Caller:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stopping Easements Through Copyright</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/stopping-easements-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 15:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/stopping-easements-copyright/</guid>
      <description>A Canadian artist, Peter von Tiesenhausen, has effectively stopped a pipeline through his 800 acre property by covering it with artwork and copyrighting the top six inches of his land as an artwork. Companies could gain use of his property through easements, but they are severely limited by the addition of a copyright. For lawyers and those who believe in property rights, easements are contentious.
Here is some more:
I am assuming they are in court, but I plan to read more about the claims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAA Device Rules and the Continuing Problem of Spectrum Interference</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/faa-device-rules-and-the-continuing-problem-of-spectrum-interference/</guid>
      <description>This was bound to happen: the proliferation of mobile devices is beginning to cause the “incidents” involving airline passengers to rack up. From Nick Bilton:
At issue is the largely unproven idea that tablets and phones interfere with a plane’s computers and communication devices. But, the asymmetry in rules for flight and takeoff is especially peculiar. When electromagnetic interference does happen with mobile devices, it is usually limited to a narrowband of the spectrum, due to inadequate filtering, tuning, or poor frequency control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon &amp; Their Taxes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 21:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/amazon-their-taxes/</guid>
      <description>Reuters is reporting on the history and legal problems of Amazon’s taxes. Apparently, last year the IRS demanded $1.5 billion in back-taxes from “transfer pricing [of their] our foreign subsidiaries,” amounting to just under a tenth of their gross annual profit.
The article doesn’t take much knowledge of tax law to understand, but for the tl:dr crowd, here is the gist:
In 1999, Amazon began to bring foreign profits home from their French and British operations to balance the losses in the US, which at the time amounted to over $1 billion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inseparability of Rights and Duties</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:48:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-inseparability-of-rights-and-duties/</guid>
      <description>On rights and duties by James Otteson:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multistakeholder Meeting Illuminates Various Problems of Objectivity</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 19:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-multistakeholder-meeting-illuminates-various-problems-of-objectivity/</guid>
      <description>At the NTIA Multistakeholder Meeting this week, it was suggested that all those studies submitted and funded by an outside source be disclosed. Later, when the issue of objectivity came up again, it was suggested that the group should rely on professors to provide objective views. While I am for disclosure in practice and not necessarily against the academy, both of the suggestions belie a flawed, but pervasive, vision on the connection between objectivity and research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Richard Pipes’ “Property and Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>No society has ever existed without some kind of property, the vision of an ideal propertyless world must be grounded not in collective memory but in a collective longing. p 5
  Politics for those in The Republic were largely a matter of custom, not law. Hence for Plato, the ideal state would have no statutes. According to Plutarch, Lycurgus would not permit the rules he laid down for Sparta to be committed to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Filter Bubble Thesis’ Popped by Real-world Evidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 19:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/filter-bubble-thesis-popped-by-real-world-evidence/</guid>
      <description>SOPA and PIPA overshadowed a number of newsworthy releases at the end of January, and in the scuffle, a study dissecting Facebook’s information networks seemed to have been lost. However, it lobbed an empirical salvo in the Filter Bubble war.
Working with Facebook, Eytan Bakshy, a newly-minted PhD in information theory, ran an experiment on the social network to better understand how individuals share information through their web of relations. Conducted over seven weeks in the summer of 2010, the experiment randomly suppressed links shared through the Facebook “Like” button—so some users wouldn’t see links that would normally have appeared in the Facebook “News Feed” of content shared by their friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The police state began with the Inquisition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/the-police-state-began-with-the-inquisition/</guid>
      <description>This article, and the book that it is based on, seem hugely provocative:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
