<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:55:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What unknown technological invention will have a huge impact on the future? A compilation of Reddit answers.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/what-unknown-technological-invention-will-have-a-huge-impact-on-the-future-a-compilation-of-reddit-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/what-unknown-technological-invention-will-have-a-huge-impact-on-the-future-a-compilation-of-reddit-answers/</guid>
      <description>On Reddit, it was asked, what’s a relatively unknown technological invention that will have a huge impact on the future? As expected, there were countless great examples, so I compiled them below and tried to organize them by topic.
Biotechnology and medicine
 Microgel will be used to repair spines Research into bacteriophages could cure antibiotic resistant bacteria such as MRSA. Gene therapy will wildly proliferate. Wireless ECG machines will be more widely used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress Studies, Some Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>When I read through Patrick Collison and Tyler Cowen’s article in The Atlantic calling for a new science of progress that studies “successful people, organizations, institutions, policies, and cultures,” my first reaction was, yes of course, that needs to be done. And then the negative responses came in, minimizing the push from Collison and Cowen because, as the critics had argued, management theory and entrepreneurial studies and even history is doing the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing Tastes in the Top 40 &amp; Some Economics of Music</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 15:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/changing-tastes-top-40-media-economics/</guid>
      <description>A back and forth has popped up about the Top 40. It began with Libby Jacobson comparing a Top 40 list from 1996 and today. As she points out, even though only Alanis Morissette was the only one to have two songs in the Top 40, today the Top 40 shows much less variety:
Ultimately, Jacobson concludes that “pop music is converging both in terms of style/sound and in terms of the talent &amp;amp; personalities producing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation, Robot Economics &amp; Employment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</guid>
      <description>David Autor just released a new paper exploring the intellectual development and paradoxes in machine displacement of labor. The paper is especially timely given the broad discussion of labor markets economics is having post downturn.
It begins with a quote from the better of Polanyi brothers, Michael, who observed, “We can know more than we can tell… The skill of a driver cannot be replaced by a thorough schooling in the theory of the motorcar; the knowledge I have of my own body differs altogether from the knowledge of its physiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (Robot) Revolution Will be Televised</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 21:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/robot-revolution-will-televised/</guid>
      <description>A lot of stories about robot economics have popped up in the past couple weeks. Here is a couple of the most interesting:
 Human Needs Not Apply (Video) AI, Robotics, and the Future of Jobs from Pew Should your robot driver kill you to save a child’s life? As machines take on more human work, what’s left for us? from Pew  And for those who are interested, there is a blog dedicated to robot economics, called appropriately enough RobotEconomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grab for the Graph</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 17:45:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/the-grab-for-the-graph/</guid>
      <description>Connecting search with social would be a huge step to completing the social graph. Currently Facebook has the lead on this one, but if Google is able to sidestep the privacy issues, which have been thorny, they could capture the pie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markets in Eveything Google Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</guid>
      <description>Google is developing a data exchange:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
