<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labor Markets on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/labor-markets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labor Markets on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 17:23:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/labor-markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Basics of Euvoluntary Exchange</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 17:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/basics-euvoluntary-exchange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samuel Wilson’s prodigious and interesting output at &lt;a href=&#34;http://euvoluntaryexchange.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary Exchange&lt;/a&gt; lead me to two articles by Michael Munger, the source of the blog’s name and focus. The first article “&lt;a href=&#34;http://people.duke.edu/~munger/euvol.pdf&#34;&gt;Euvoluntary or Not, Exchange is Just&lt;/a&gt;” is fascinating. Here is the main thesis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Munger, euvoluntary exchange is the name given to any any truly voluntary exchange that leaves both parties better off than before. To be truly voluntary or euvoluntary, the exchange requires&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation, Robot Economics &amp; Employment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/automation-robot-economics-employment/</guid>
      <description>David Autor just released a new paper exploring the intellectual development and paradoxes in machine displacement of labor. The paper is especially timely given the broad discussion of labor markets economics is having post downturn.
It begins with a quote from the better of Polanyi brothers, Michael, who observed, “We can know more than we can tell… The skill of a driver cannot be replaced by a thorough schooling in the theory of the motorcar; the knowledge I have of my own body differs altogether from the knowledge of its physiology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in the 1700s Was Very Poor</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 00:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2013/life-in-the-1700s-was-very-poor/</guid>
      <description>The natural state of humanity is poverty, not abundance. Poor, nasty brutish and short was the way of life for nearly until 250 years ago, especially poor. Here was life in the early 1700s, for example:
 Every item of clothing was made by hand to fit the consumer. Suits made like this today costs around $4,000. Consider affording that on subsistence wages.  In France, it was common for poor laborers to not wear shoes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
