<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>innovation on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in innovation on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:56:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Progress Studies, Some Initial Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 15:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/progress-studies-some-initial-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>When I read through Patrick Collison and Tyler Cowen’s article in The Atlantic calling for a new science of progress that studies “successful people, organizations, institutions, policies, and cultures,” my first reaction was, yes of course, that needs to be done. And then the negative responses came in, minimizing the push from Collison and Cowen because, as the critics had argued, management theory and entrepreneurial studies and even history is doing the job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Technology Matters For Tech Policy And Growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dan Wang has &lt;a href=&#34;https://danwang.co/how-technology-grows/&#34;&gt;a new post&lt;/a&gt; titled “How Technology Grows (a restatement of definite optimism)” and it is characteristically good. For tech policy wonks and policymakers, put it in your queue. The essay clocks in at 7500 words, but there’s a lot to glean from the piece. Indeed, he puts into words a number of ideas I’ve been wanting to write about. To set the stage, he begins first by defining what we mean by technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he rightly points out, the United States has, for various reasons, set aside the focus on process knowledge. Where this is especially evident comes in our manufacturing base:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/blog/us-needs-more-manufactured-exports&#34;&gt;an outlier among&lt;/a&gt; rich countries when it comes to manufacturing exports. It needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did The Facebook Stock Drop Last Week? Some Economics Of Decision-making</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 22:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/why-did-the-facebook-stock-drop-last-week-some-economics-of-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;A curious thing happened last week. Facebook’s stock, which had seem to have weathered the 2018 controversies, took a beating. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In the Washington Post, Craig Timberg and Elizabeth Dwoskin &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/07/26/how-years-privacy-controversies-finally-caught-up-with-facebook/?utm_term=.33e4676e4d41&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;explained&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;that the stock market drop was representative of a larger wave:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Jeff Chester of the Center for Digital Democracy piled on, describing the drop as “a privacy wake-up call that the markets are delivering to Mark Zuckerberg.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;But the downward pressure was driven by more fundamental changes. Simply put, Facebook missed its earnings target. But it is important to peer into why the company didn’t meet those targets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
