<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Neutrality on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/network-neutrality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Neutrality on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:43:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/network-neutrality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two years on, it is clear that the network neutrality fight was meta-miserable</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2020/two-years-on-it-is-clear-that-the-network-neutrality-fight-was-meta-miserable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2020/two-years-on-it-is-clear-that-the-network-neutrality-fight-was-meta-miserable/</guid>
      <description>Eric Weinstein’s recent conversation with Balaji Srinivasan reminded me of today’s auspicious anniversary. On this date, two years ago, the Restoring Internet Freedom Order took effect, effectively ending the Open Internet Order from the Obama Era.
Looking back, I can confidently say that the policy discussion surrounding network neutrality failed meta-miserably. Us policy wonks need to do better and a good first step would be the embrace of prediction tournaments and policy bets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Competition in Network Neutrality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/role-competition-network-neutrality/</guid>
      <description>Alissa Cooper, formerly at CDT and now at Cisco, wrote her PhD dissertation on network neutrality practices in the US and the UK. Here is an interesting tidbit from her abstract:
In many European countries, unbundling has lead to competition among providers. While this has put downward pressure on consumer prices, investment in the backbone is far lower. Altogether, these industry features often lead companies pricing data since their margins are low, thus leading to very schemes that network neutrality advocates deplore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill Profiles Gigi Sohn</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/hill-profiles-gigi-sohn/</guid>
      <description>Julian Hattem has a profile of Gigi Sohn, charting her influence over the network neutrality debate. The former head of an advocacy organization now leads from the inside:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s The FCC’s Rush on New Net Neutrality Rules?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 21:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/whats-fccs-rush-new-net-neutrality-rules/</guid>
      <description>Network neutrality rules have failed to pass Congress and the courts countless times, so what’s the FCC’s rush now? Scott Cleland explores in an op-ed at the Daily Caller:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
