<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:54:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Esoteric Reading of LM Sacasas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</guid>
      <description>After reading LM Sacasas’ recent piece on moral communities, I couldn’t help but wonder if the piece was written in the esoteric mode.
Let me explain by some meandering.
Now, I am surely going to butcher his argument, so take a read of it yourself, but there is a bit of an interesting call and response structure to the piece. He begins with commentary on “frequent deployment of the rhetorical we,” in discussions over the morality of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Technology Matters For Tech Policy And Growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dan Wang has &lt;a href=&#34;https://danwang.co/how-technology-grows/&#34;&gt;a new post&lt;/a&gt; titled “How Technology Grows (a restatement of definite optimism)” and it is characteristically good. For tech policy wonks and policymakers, put it in your queue. The essay clocks in at 7500 words, but there’s a lot to glean from the piece. Indeed, he puts into words a number of ideas I’ve been wanting to write about. To set the stage, he begins first by defining what we mean by technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he rightly points out, the United States has, for various reasons, set aside the focus on process knowledge. Where this is especially evident comes in our manufacturing base:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/blog/us-needs-more-manufactured-exports&#34;&gt;an outlier among&lt;/a&gt; rich countries when it comes to manufacturing exports. It needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
