<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation &amp;amp; Entrepreneurship on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/innovation-amp-entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation &amp;amp; Entrepreneurship on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:16:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/innovation-amp-entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Entrepreneurial State, Some Brief Comments</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/the-entrepreneurial-state-some-brief-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 14:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/the-entrepreneurial-state-some-brief-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Economist Mariana Mazzucato has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/mariana-mazzucato?fbclid=IwAR2OPxV-MNLGWJpaCSivm35lD9xkKVcSfYNB0YxO-Q9qNv9hrAAmoruiNR0&#34;&gt;full spread in the Wired UK&lt;/a&gt; humbling suggesting that she “has a plan to fix capitalism.” The plan is an outgrowth of her 2013 book &lt;em&gt;The Entrepreneurial State&lt;/em&gt;, which contends that government involvement in research and development (R&amp;amp;D), loans, and other business subsidies are the true drivers of innovation, not the private sector. Her plan is simple: governments need to do better on funding innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that the government is massively involved in innovation and for good reason. Open any introductory economics text and you’re likely to see an argument for why. Private actors are short sighted and often fail to plan for the long term by investing in R&amp;amp;D that will lead to technological progress. Basic research also might lead to advances or products outside of the company’s niche. Knowing that they won’t be able to capture all of the gains from research, private entities will choose a lower level of investment than is optimal, leading to a market failure. Governments solve this market failure by allocating resources to expanding scientific and technological knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Mazzucato might be finding an audience with policy makers in the UK and doers in Silicon Valley, innovation economists are a little more wary of her state first theory of innovation. Here are some things worth considering when reading her work:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are good reasons to be skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/there-are-good-reasons-to-be-skeptical-that-automation-will-unravel-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to the threat of automation, I agree with Ryan Khurana: “From self-driving car crashes to failed workplace algorithms, many AI tools fail to perform simple tasks humans excel at, let alone far surpass us in every way.” Like myself, he is skeptical that automation will unravel the labor market, pointing out that “[The] conflation of what AI ‘may one day do’ with the much more mundane ‘what software can do today’ creates a powerful narrative around automation that accepts no refutation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Technology Matters For Tech Policy And Growth</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 19:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-definition-of-technology-matters-for-tech-policy-and-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dan Wang has &lt;a href=&#34;https://danwang.co/how-technology-grows/&#34;&gt;a new post&lt;/a&gt; titled “How Technology Grows (a restatement of definite optimism)” and it is characteristically good. For tech policy wonks and policymakers, put it in your queue. The essay clocks in at 7500 words, but there’s a lot to glean from the piece. Indeed, he puts into words a number of ideas I’ve been wanting to write about. To set the stage, he begins first by defining what we mean by technology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he rightly points out, the United States has, for various reasons, set aside the focus on process knowledge. Where this is especially evident comes in our manufacturing base:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfr.org/blog/us-needs-more-manufactured-exports&#34;&gt;an outlier among&lt;/a&gt; rich countries when it comes to manufacturing exports. It needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
