<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advertising on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/advertising/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advertising on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:48:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/advertising/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An exploration of the limits of advertising byway of a brief review of the effects literature</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/advertising-uneasy-persuasion-or-means-of-social-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 12:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/advertising-uneasy-persuasion-or-means-of-social-engineering/</guid>
      <description>[DRAFT: Monday, August 19, 2019]
The Domain Of The Critique
If you follow the major tech publications, you would think that the advertising of today is a powerful new weapon that desperately needs to be reigned in.
NYT technology reporter Natasha Singer laid it out, “What is at stake here isn’t privacy, the right not to be observed. It’s how companies can use our data to invisibly shunt us in directions that may benefit them more than us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micropayments, The News, &amp; Friction Free Browsing</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 19:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2015/micropayments-news-friction-free-browsing/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week I heard Walter Isaacson delve into his new book, “The Innovators,” at the American Enterprise Institute. In discussion, he lamented the development of the various business models in online journalism, and content generally, arguing forcefully for micropayments in their place. In a LinkedIn article on the same subject, he explains:
Even though I am not in the prediction business, I am highly skeptical that micropayments will become widespread for a number of reasons, none of which are particularly new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “If You’re Not Paying, You Are The Product” Is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 01:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/saying-youre-paying-product-wrong/</guid>
      <description>This week I heard the phrase that haunts tech policy. You know it. _If you’re not paying for the product, you are the product. _
Concise? Yes. But wrong.
The product is actually an ad, positioned on the site and tailored for you. Countless weeklies across the US run under a free model and have done so for decades. The New York Times has defrayed the expense of printing by ad supplement since its beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markets in Eveything Google Edition</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/markets-in-eveything-google-edition/</guid>
      <description>Google is developing a data exchange:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and iAd</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2010/apple-and-iad/</guid>
      <description>I really don’t know how this went past me, but I was watching Fast Money today and Kaminsky made note of Apple going into direct search. To make this a little more solid, look at this,
The always insightful Picard makes this more tangible:
Only time will allow us to understand how this is going to work out, but regardless, it is an interesting time to be in media.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
