<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy &amp;amp; Cyber-Libertarianism on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/philosophy-amp-cyber-libertarianism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy &amp;amp; Cyber-Libertarianism on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:54:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/philosophy-amp-cyber-libertarianism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Esoteric Reading of LM Sacasas</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/an-esoteric-reading-of-lm-sacasas/</guid>
      <description>After reading LM Sacasas’ recent piece on moral communities, I couldn’t help but wonder if the piece was written in the esoteric mode.
Let me explain by some meandering.
Now, I am surely going to butcher his argument, so take a read of it yourself, but there is a bit of an interesting call and response structure to the piece. He begins with commentary on “frequent deployment of the rhetorical we,” in discussions over the morality of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Short Responses To The Pacing Problem</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/three-short-responses-to-the-pacing-problem/</guid>
      <description>Contemporary tech criticism displays an anti-nostalgia. Instead of being reverent for the past, anxiety about the future abounds. In these visions, the future is imagined as a strange, foreign land, beset with problems. And yet, to quote that old adage, tomorrow is the visitor that is always coming but never arrives. The future never arrives because we are assembling it today.
The distance between the now and the future finds its hook in tech policy in the pacing problem, a term describing the mismatch between advancing technologies and society’s efforts to cope with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Cathy O’Neil’s &#34;Weapons of Math Destruction&#34;</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/book-review-cathy-oneils-weapons-of-math-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/book-review-cathy-oneils-weapons-of-math-destruction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;To read Cathy O’Neil’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;(2016) is to experience another in a line of progressive pugilists of the technological age. Where Tim Wu took on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Future-Internet-How-Stop/dp/0300151241&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;the future of the Internet&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and Evgeny Morozov &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Net-Delusion-Dark-Internet-Freedom/dp/1610391063&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;chided online slactivism&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, O’Neil takes on algorithms, or what she has dubbed weapons of math destruction (WMD).&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;O’Neil’s book came at just the right moment in 2016. It sounded the alarm about big data just as it was becoming a topic for public discussion. And now, two years later, her worries seem prescient. As she explains in the introduction,&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;O’Neil is explicit about laying out the blame at the feet of the WMDs, “You cannot appeal to a WMD. That’s part of their fearsome power. They do not listen.” Yet, these models aren’t deployed and adopted in a frictionless environment. Instead, they “reflect goals and ideology” as O’Neil readily admits. Where &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Weapons of Math Destruction &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;falters is that it ascribes too much agency to algorithms in places, and in doing so misses the broader politics behind algorithmic decision making.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Techno-optimism</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/in-defense-of-techno-optimism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 18:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/in-defense-of-techno-optimism/</guid>
      <description>Many are understandably pessimistic about platforms and technology. This year has been a tough one, from Cambridge Analytica and Russian trolls to the implementation of GDPR and data breaches galore.
Those who think about the world, about the problems that we see every day, and about their own place in it, will quickly realize the immense frailty of humankind. Fear and worry makes sense. We are flawed, each one of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Online Public Sphere or: Facebook, Google, Reddit, and Twitter also support positive communities</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2018/the-online-public-sphere-or-facebook-google-reddit-and-twitter-also-support-positive-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;In cleaning up my desk this weekend, I chanced upon an old notebook and like many times before I began to transcribe the notes. It was short, so I got to the end within a couple of minutes. The last page was scribbled with the German term Öffentlichkeit (public sphere), a couple sentences on Hannah Arendt, and a paragraph about Norberto Bobbio’s view of public and private. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Then I remembered. Yep. This is the missing notebook from a class on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zizi.people.uic.edu/Site/Courses_files/DemInDigAgeSyllabus.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;democracy in the digital age&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.   &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Serendipitously, a couple of hours later, William Freeland alerted me to Franklin Foer’s newest piece in The Atlantic titled “&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/07/the-death-of-the-public-square/564506/?utm_content=edit-promo&amp;amp;utm_campaign=the-atlantic&amp;amp;utm_term=2018-07-06T16%3A04%3A10&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Death of the Public Square&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.” Foer is the author of “World Without Mind: The Existential Threat of Big Tech,” and if you want a good take on that book, check out Adam Thierer’s &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reason.com/archives/2017/12/23/how-to-write-a-tech-panic-mani&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;review in Reason&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Much like the book, this Atlantic piece wades into techno ruin porn but focuses instead on the public sphere:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
