<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes &amp;amp; Quotes on Will Rinehart</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/notes-amp-quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes &amp;amp; Quotes on Will Rinehart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Will Rinehart | economist, speaker, and analyst of tech policy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 14:45:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/notes-amp-quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links For Thursday, September 5, 2019</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/links-for-thursday-september-5-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 14:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/links-for-thursday-september-5-2019/</guid>
      <description>Will Oremus dissects that often repeated phrase, if you aren’t paying, you’re the product. While the piece is stellar, I don’t really agree with Oremus when he says that an alternative vision would “view ourselves as customers of Facebook, paying with our time, attention, and data instead of with money.” That assumes a payment system. Instead we should think of it as exchange. For better or worse, we still use the rhetoric of payments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studies Exploring GPS Adoption</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2019/studies-exploring-gps-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 13:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2019/studies-exploring-gps-adoption/</guid>
      <description>I’m a couple of chapters into reading Re-Engineering Humanity from Brett Frischmann and Evan Selinger, which includes a discussion of the effects of GPS. So, I thought I would take a look at the literature. “Results showed that GPS users traveled longer distances and made more stops during the walk than map users and direct-experience participants. Also, GPS users traveled more slowly, made larger direction errors, drew sketch maps with poorer topological accuracy, and rated wayfinding tasks as more difficult than direct-experience participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Eli Pariser’s “The Filter Bubble: What the Internet Is Hiding from You”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 20:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2014/notes-quotes-eli-parisers-filter-bubble-internet-hiding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“To my preteen self, it seemed clear that the Internet was going to democratize the world, connecting us with better information and the power to act on it. The California futurists and techno-optimists in those pages spoke with a clear-eyed certainty; an inevitable, irresistible revolution was just around the corner, one that would flatten society, unseat the elites, and usher in a kind of freewheeling global utopia.” pg 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Filter Bubble introduces three dynamics we’ve never dealt with before: first, you are alone in it, as it is you own personal bubble. Second, it is invisible in its actions. Finally, you don’t choose to enter into the bubble. pp 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the cost of communication over large distances and to large groups of people has plummeted, we’re increasingly unable to attend to it all,” leading to what blogger and media analyst Steve Rubel calls the attention crash. p 11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of personalization is appealing as a “return to a Ptolemaic universe in which the sun and everything else revolves around us.” p 12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the filter bubble, there’s less room for the chance encounters that bring insight and learning” p 15 My reaction: &lt;em&gt;What does Kirzner have to say about this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be the author of your life, professor Yochai Benkler argues, you have to be aware of a diverse array of options and lifestyles. When you enter a filter bubble, you’re letting companies that construct it choose which options you’re aware of. You may think that you’re the captain of your own destiny, but personalization can lead you down a road to a kind of informational determinism in which what you’ve clicked on in the past determines what you see next—a Web history you’re doomed to repeat.” p 16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Putnam defined two kinds of social capital: in-group oriented bonding capital represents those events when you meet an old friend, while bridging capital occurs when lots of people from different backgrounds come together to meet each other, like in a townhall. p 17&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought Lecture 1 and 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 22:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-on-mark-thomas-history-of-economic-thought-lecture-1-and-2/</guid>
      <description>I have been watching Mark Thoma’s History of Economic Thought class on YouTube for a refresher on the subject. Here are my notes:
  Probably the most important part for the creation of the modern state is the creation of a unified market. True, the places that did open up to trade first were the Italian city states, but soon after the Dutch began to create cost-less trade networks, and then followed England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Daniel Boorstin’s “The Republic of Technology”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-daniel-boorstins-the-republic-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>“An athlete of steel and iron with not a superfluous ounce of metal on it” exclaimed William Dean Howells when he recalled the gigantic 700-ton Corliss steam engine that towered over Machinery Hall at the Philadelphia International Exhibition. A festive crowd cheered as the engine set in motion a wonderful assortment of machines—pumping water, combing wool, spinning cotton, tearing hemp, printing newspapers, lithographing wallpaper, sewing cloth, folding envelopes, sawing logs, shaping wood, making shoes—8,000 machines spread over 13 acres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Richard Pipes’ “Property and Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-richard-pipes-property-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>No society has ever existed without some kind of property, the vision of an ideal propertyless world must be grounded not in collective memory but in a collective longing. p 5
  Politics for those in The Republic were largely a matter of custom, not law. Hence for Plato, the ideal state would have no statutes. According to Plutarch, Lycurgus would not permit the rules he laid down for Sparta to be committed to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes to Ithiel de Sola Pool’s “Technologies of Freedom”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 18:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-to-ithiel-de-sola-pools-technologies-of-freedom/</guid>
      <description>A public network interconnecting computers must be license and, according to present interpretations of the 1934 Communications Act, may be denied a license if the government does not believe that it serves “the public convenience, interest, or necessity” p. 3 The Constitution, in Article 1, Section 8, gives the federal government the right to regulate interstate commerce, but in the First Amendment, equally explicitly, it excludes one kind of commerce, namely communication, from government authority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Thomas P. Hughes “American Genesis”</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 21:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-thomas-p-hughes-american-genesis/</guid>
      <description>When more histories of technology that take the critical stance of the best histories of politics are written, American will realize that not only their remarkable achievements but many of their deep and persistent problems arise, in the name of order, system, and control, from the mechanization and systematization of life and from the sacrifice of the organic and the spontaneous p 4 As historian and social critic Lewis Mumford so eloquently insisted decades ago, technology is both shaper of, and is shaped by, values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Desmond Morris’ The Human Zoo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 04:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-desmond-morris-the-human-zoo/</guid>
      <description>What is surprising is that the bloated super-tribes have survived at all and, what is more, survived so well. This is not something we should accept simple because we are sitting here in the twentieth century, it is something we should marvel at. It is an astonishing testimony to our incredible ingenuity, tenacity and plasticity as a species. How on earth did we manage it? If our hunting ancestors had really been ruthless, greedy tyrants, loaded with ‘original sin’, the human success story would have petered out long ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes &amp; Quotes from Joel Mokyr’s Lever of Riches</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 16:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2012/notes-quotes-from-joel-mokyrs-lever-of-riches/</guid>
      <description>Economic growth can happen in one of four ways: 1) Solovian growth where capital accumulation occurs at a faster rate than growth of the labor force so each worker has more capital to work with, 2) Smithian growth where there is increase in trade, 3) Scale or sizing effects, or 4) Schumpeterian growth, that is, capitalist expansion deriving from continuous though fluctuating, technological change and innovation financed through the extension of credit Economists typically approach the explanation of technological change by considering the relationship between demand and supply variables, research and development and productivity growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes and Quotes on ‘The Foucault Effect: Studies in Governmentality</title>
      <link>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 22:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/2011/notes-and-quotes-on-the-foucault-effect-studies-in-governmentality/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of weeks, I have been become fascinated with the the history of policing, an area of dire import for libertarians of all stripes. Originally, the word police was synonymous with policy as we know it today e.g. civil administration, but slowly it began to take a different tact around the time when the modern state and economy were coming into their own. According to the etymology dictionary, the first force so-named in England was the Marine Police, set up 1798 to protect merchandise at the Port of London.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
